. >> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYBODY.
WELCOME TO THE FEBRUARY 24TH 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
ROLL. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER
FIELDER PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESIDENT SUPERVISOR
MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR PRESENCE
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT
ALL MEMBERS ARE PRESENT GREAT. THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE ROMA TO SALONI WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL
INHABITANTS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA.
AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE
WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE RAW MATERIAL OWNERS HAVE NEVER
CEDED LOST OR FORGOTTEN THEIR RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE
CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE. AS WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO
RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE
RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR
TRADITIONAL HOMELAND. WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY
ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS, ELDERS AND RELATIVES THE
PARAMETERS OF ANY COMMUNITY AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR
SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE? I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES, AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH
IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD, INDIVISIBLE WITH LIBERTY
AND JUSTICE FOR ALL. >> ON BEHALF OF OUR BOARD I
WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF AT US OF GOV TV TODAY THAT'S
PARTICULARLY JEANETTE EGAN LOUTH.
THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR MEETINGS AND MAKE THE
TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE PUBLIC ONLINE.
MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY COMMUNICATIONS?
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL TO ATTEND THIS MEETING IN THE
BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER IN PERSON.
>> AND WHEN YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO BE HERE, YOU CAN CATCH THE
PROCEEDING ON S.F. GOVEE TV'S CHANNEL 26 WHERE YOU CAN VIEW
THE LIVE STREAM AT W W W DOT S.F. GOV ETV TALK YOU'D LIKE TO
IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO SUBMIT PUBLIC COMMENT AND EITHER
WRITING OR BY USING THE POSTAL SERVICE YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL
TO BOSSI AT F GOV DAWG OR USE THE POSTAL SERVICE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B
GOOD PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA
94102. IF YOU'D LIKE TO MAKE A
REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A FUTURE MEETING UNDER THE
AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE
ASSISTANCE, CONTACT THE CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS
DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING (415) 554-5184.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
LET'S GO TO APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
>> APPROVAL OF THE JANUARY 13TH, 2026 BOARD MEETING
MINUTES. >> COLLEAGUES, CAN I HAVE A
MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED BY CHEN
SECONDED BY MAHMUD. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN
I'M A SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR HUANG WONG ONG
EITHER ARE ELIMINATED WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE
APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S
GO TO THE CONSENT AGENDA ITEMS ONE THROUGH SIX ITEMS ONE
THROUGH SIX ARE ON CONSENT. THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO
BE ROUTINE. IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY
BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH SIX
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
AND SUPERVISOR HUANG HUANG EITHER ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK
LET'S GO TO UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER SEVEN
ITEM SEVEN THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO APPROVE A HOTEL DEVELOPMENT
INCENTIVE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY AND BESPOKE HOSPITALITY
LLC FOR THE HURST HOTEL DEVELOPMENT PROJECT TO PROVIDE
40 MILLION IN FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE IN NET PRESENT VALUE
OVER 20 YEARS AS A PERCENTAGE OF THE NEW TRANSIENT OCCUPANCY
TAXES THE CITY ACTUALLY RECEIVES FROM OCCUPANCY OF
GUEST ROOMS IN A PROPOSED NEW HOTEL RELATED TO THE
DEVELOPMENT AND OPERATION OF A PROJECT ON CERTAIN REAL
PROPERTY KNOWN AS FIFTH THIRD STREET AND 17 THROUGH 29 THIRD
STREET TO WAIVE CHAPTER 21 OF THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE
AND CERTAIN SECTIONS OF THE LABOR EMPLOYMENT CODE TO RATIFY
PASSED AND TO AUTHORIZE FUTURE ACTIONS IN FURTHERANCE OF THIS
ORDINANCE AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM SEVEN SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN NO
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER NO. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MIDDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
THERE ARE NINE EYES AND TWO NOSE WITH SUPERVISORS CHAN
AND FIELDER VOTING NO THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER EIGHT ITEM EIGHT THIS IS
AN ORDINANCE TO APPROPRIATE 18.5 MILLION OF FUND BALANCE
FROM THE PORT HARBOR FUND TO THE PORT OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR
STABILIZATION AND DISPOSAL OF DRY DOCKS AND OTHER SHIPMENT
IMPROVEMENTS AND SAFETY MEASURES IN FISCAL YEAR 2025
THROUGH 2026. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
EIGHT SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN HI MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISE OR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EITHER ARE LEBANESE WITHOUT OBJECTION
THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO APPROPRIATE APPROXIMATELY 311,000 FROM THE GENERAL
RESERVE TO THE MUNICIPAL TRANSPORTATION AGENCY TO
SUPPORT FREE ONE HOUR PARKING IN THE PORTSMOUTH SQUARE
PARKING GARAGE FEBRUARY EIGHTH THROUGH MARCH 8TH 2026
AND TRANSIT FARES FOR THE LUNAR NEW YEAR PARADE ON MARCH 7TH,
2026 OF FISCAL YEAR 2025 THROUGH 2026.
AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM TEN ITEM TEN RESOLUTION TO
ADOPT A FIXED TWO YEAR BUDGETARY CYCLE FOR THE
FOLLOWING CITY DEPARTMENTS AIRPORT PORT AND THE PUBLIC
UTILITIES COMMISSION FOR FISCAL YEAR 2026 THROUGH 2027 AND 2027
THROUGH 2028 AND TO DEFINE TERMS AND TO SET DEADLINES
AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS
11 THROUGH 13 TOGETHER ITEM E ITEMS 11 THROUGH 13 ARE THREE
RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE TERMS
AND CONDITIONS AND AUTHORIZE THE GENERAL MANAGER OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION AND OR THE DIRECTOR
OF PROPERTY TO EXECUTE A PURCHASE AND SALE AGREEMENT
AND EASEMENT DEED WITH VARIOUS ENTITIES FOR ITEM 11 WITH KATIE
CHANG FOR THE ACQUISITION OF NINE POINT TWO SQUARE FOOT
EASEMENT FOR SUBSURFACE SEWER TUNNEL UNDER THE UNDER
AND ACROSS A PORTION OF 491 GAVIN STREET SAN FRANCISCO FOR
A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 2500 FOR ITEM 12 THIS IS WITH THE ROBERT SUI
AND TO AND LEE SUI AS TRUSTEES OF THE SUI FAMILY TRUST FOR THE
ACQUISITION OF A 298.2FT2 EASEMENT FOR A SUBSURFACE SEWER
TUNNEL UNDER THE UNDER AND ACROSS A PORTION OF 495
GAVIN STREET SAN FRANCISCO FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 25,000
AND FOR ITEM 11 WITH WHALEN RU WAY HALL AT ALL FOR THE
ACQUISITION OF A 693.2FT2 EASEMENT FOR A SUBSURFACE SEWER
TUNNEL UNDER AN ACROSS A PORTION KNOWN AS 499 GAVIN
STREET SAN FRANCISCO FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 32,000 AND TO
ADOPT THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS FOR EACH ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
14. >> ITEM 14 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO RETROACTIVELY APPROVE THE 50TH AMENDMENT TO THE TREASURE
ISLAND AND STRUCTURES MASTER LEASE BETWEEN THE TREASURE
ISLAND DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY AND THE UNITED STATES NAVY TO
EXTEND THE TERM FOR ONE YEAR TO COMMENCE DECEMBER 1ST 2025 FOR
A TOTAL TERM OF NOVEMBER 19TH 1998 THROUGH NOVEMBER 30TH 2026
. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 15.
ITEM 15 THIS RESOLUTION APPROVES THE SECOND AMENDMENT
TO A CONTRACT BETWEEN THE CITY AND BY TALENT FOR BLOOD
AND BLOOD PRODUCTS FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH TO
EXTEND THE CONTRACT BY FIVE YEARS FOR A TOTAL TERM OF TEN
YEARS OCTOBER 1ST, 2021 THROUGH SEPTEMBER 30TH 2031 TO INCREASE
THE CONTRACT AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 18.2 MILLION FOR
A TOTAL AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 28.2 MILLION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
16. >> ITEM 16 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR OF PROPERTY TO EXECUTE
A FIRST AMENDMENT TO AN OFFICE LEASE FOR THE CONTINUED USE OF
OFFICE SPACE LOCATED AT 258 A LAGUNA HONDA BOULEVARD WITH CHU
LAGUNA LLC AS LANDLORD WITH AN ESTIMATED COMMENCEMENT DATE OF
MARCH 1ST, 2026 AND TO TERMINATE ON FEBRUARY 28TH 2029
AT A MONTHLY BASE RENT OF APPROXIMATELY 4825 FOR A TOTAL
ANNUAL BASE RENT OF 58,000 INCREASED BY APPROXIMATELY
$145.50 AND $148.50 PER MONTH IN THE SECOND AND THIRD YEARS
RESPECTIVELY WITH ONE THREE YEAR OPTION TO EXTEND SAME
HOUSE SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 17 ITEM
17 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO RETROFIT ACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE
DEPARTMENT OF THE ENVIRONMENT TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND AN
APPROXIMATE $299,000 GRANT FROM THE TECH CLEAN CALIFORNIA FOR
THE PERIOD BEGINNING ON OR ABOUT JANUARY 20TH 2026 THROUGH
MARCH 31ST 2027 TO PROVIDE HEAT PUMP WATER HEATERS AS PART OF
RENOVATION AND REPAIR PROJECTS THROUGH THE LOW INCOME
INVESTMENT FUNDS. CHILD CARE FACILITIES FUND
AND TO EXPAND THE REACH OF ELECTRIFICATION TRAINING TO
ORGANIZATIONS AND CONTRACTORS WORKING IN HOUSING
REHABILITATION PROGRAMS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL 18 ITEM 18 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
APPROVE THE 10TH AMENDMENT TO A CONTRACT AT CONTRACT NUMBER SFM
TO DASH 2016 THROUGH 17 PARATRANSIT BROKER
AND OPERATING AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY AND TRANSDEV SERVICES
INC TO PROVIDE PARATRANSIT SERVICES TO EXTEND THE TERM BY
TWO YEARS JUNE 30TH 2026 FOR A TOTAL TERM JULY 1ST 2016
THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2028 AND TO INCREASE THE AMOUNT BY
APPROXIMATELY 30.8 MILLION FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY
339 MILLION. >> SAME HOUSE.
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEMS 19 AND 20 TOGETHER ITEMS 19
AND 20 ARE TWO RESOLUTIONS AND REAUTHORIZE THE EXECUTION
AND DELIVERY OF TAX EXEMPT TO LEASE REVENUE COMMERCIAL PAPER
CERTIFICATES OF PARTICIPATION AND TAXABLE LEASE REVENUE
COMMERCIAL PAPER CERTIFICATES OF PARTICIPATION FOR ITEM 19
SERIES ONE AND SERIES TWO AND SERIES ONE T AND SERIES TWO
T IN A 150 MILLION OF AGGREGATE PRINCIPAL AMOUNT TO FINANCE THE
COSTS OF THE ACQUISITION, CONSTRUCTION AND REHABILITATION
OF CAPITAL IMPROVEMENTS AND EQUIPMENT AND TO AUTHORIZE
THE DELIVERY OF AN ALTERNATE CREDIT FACILITY OF 163.5
MILLION FOR ITEM 20 THIS IS FOR SERIES THREE AND SERIES FOUR
AND SERIES 3-T AND SERIES 4-T IN 100 MILLION OF AGGREGATE
PRINCIPAL TO FINANCE THE COSTS OF THE ACQUISITION,
CONSTRUCTION AND REHABILITATION OF CAPITAL IMPROVEMENTS
AND EQUIPMENT AND TO AUTHORIZE THE MAINTENANCE OF A LIQUIDITY
FACILITY IN THE TOTAL STATED AMOUNT OF 109 MILLION.
>> SAME HOUSE SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
21. >> ITEM 21 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
TO RETROACTIVELY APPROVE A MEMORANDUM OF UNDERSTANDING AN
MOU WITH THE CITIES OF OAKLAND AND SAN JOSE AND THE COUNTIES
OF ALAMEDA CONTRA COSTA, MARIN, MONTEREY, SAN MATEO, SANTA
CLARA AND SONOMA THAT PROVIDES GOVERNANCE STRUCTURES
AND PROCEDURES FOR APPLICATION ALLOCATION AND DISTRIBUTE ATION
OF FEDERAL UAC OR THE URBAN AREAS SECURITY INITIATIVE GRANT
FUNDS TO THE BAY AREA URBAN AREA AS WELL AS FOR OTHER
FEDERAL GRANT FUNDS TO THE BAY AREA URBAN AREA AS PERMITTED
UNDER THE MOU AND TO CONTINUE SAN FRANCISCO AS THE PRIMARY
CARE GRANTEE AND FISCAL AGENT FOR UAC GRANT FUNDS TO THE BAY
AREA URBAN AREA AS WELL AS FOR OTHER GRANT FUNDS TO THE BAY
AREA URBAN AREA AS PERMITTED UNDER THE MOU.
DECEMBER 1ST, 2025 THROUGH NOVEMBER 30TH 2030.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 22 ITEM 22 THIS RESOLUTION ADDS THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET
NAME TEEN FOOL WU WEI ON JOY STREET BETWEEN CLAY
AND SACRAMENTO STREETS. IN RECOGNITION OF TEEN FOO WU
ITS CONTRIBUTION TO THE WOMEN'S RIGHTS AND ANTI-TRAFFICKING
MOVEMENT IN SAN FRANCISCO'S CHINATOWN.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEMS
23 AND 24 TOGETHER. ITEMS 23 AND 24 ARE TWO
RESOLUTIONS THAT PERTAIN TO ANY ITEM 23 THIS RESOLUTION
REAFFIRMS THE CITY'S CONTINUED EFFORTS TO ACQUIRE THE PACIFIC
GAS AND ELECTRIC COMPANY THEIR ASSETS NECESSARY TO PROVIDE
CLEAN, GREEN AND AFFORDABLE ELECTRIC POWER DELIVERY
AND SERVICE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND TO ENSURE SYSTEM
RELIABILITY, SUSTAINABILITY AND SAFETY.
AND ITEM 24 THIS RESOLUTION URGES GOVERNOR GAVIN NEWSOM
AND THE CALIFORNIA PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION TO HOLD
PACIFIC GAS AND ELECTRIC COMPANY ACCOUNTABLE FOR ITS
ACTIONS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 25.
ITEM 25 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE
TO REMOVE THE FIRE COMMISSION'S AUTHORITY TO APPOINT THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT PHYSICIAN AND TO REVISE THE REQUIRED
QUALIFICATIONS FOR ONE OF THE DEPUTY FIRE CHIEFS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 26.
>> ITEM 26. THIS ORDINANCE AMENDS THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE THE FISHERMAN'S WHARF
ENTERTAINMENT ZONE ON POWELL STREET FROM THE EMBARCADERO TO
BEACH STREET THE EMBARCADERO FROM POWELL TO TAYLOR'S STREETS
TAYLOR STREET FROM THE EMBARCADERO TO JEFFERSON STREET
JEFFERSON STREET FROM TAYLOR TO HYDE STREETS BEACH STREET FROM
HYDE TO POLK STREETS POLK STREET FROM BEACH TO NORTH
POINT STREETS NORTH POINT STREET FROM PORT TO LARKIN
STREETS LARKIN STREET FROM NORTH POINT TO BEACH STREETS
BEACH STREET FROM LARKIN TO POWELL STREETS AND ALSO HOME
AWAY AND TO AFFIRM THE SEQUEL DETERMINATION.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
OUT ON 27 ITEM 27 THIS MOTION APPOINTS COUNTY CLERK TO THE
IN-HOME SUPPORTIVE SERVICES PUBLIC AUTHORITY.
TERM ENDING MARCH 1ST 2028. >> SAME HOUSE SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEMS 28 THROUGH 31 TOGETHER ITEMS 28
THROUGH 31 ARE FOR MOTIONS THAT APPOINT SUPERVISOR SHANE CHIN
TO THE FOLLOWING AND ABIDE BODIES ITEM 28 AS AN ALTERNATE
MEMBER TO THE CALIFORNIA STATE ASSOCIATION OF COUNTIES TERM
ENDING DECEMBER 1ST, 2026 ITEM 29 AS A MEMBER TO THE CHILDREN
AND FAMILIES FIRST COMMISSION TERM ENDING OCTOBER 8TH 2026
ITEM 32 THE SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT COMMUNITY
ROUNDTABLE FOR AN INDEFINITE TERM ITEM 31 AS AN ALTERNATE
MEMBER TO THE ASSOCIATION OF BAY AREA GOVERNMENTS EXECUTIVE
BOARD TERM ENDING JUNE 30TH 2027.
>> COLLEAGUES CAN HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISOR CHEN FROM
VOTING ON THESE MATTERS MOVED BY FIELD OR SECONDED BY MAHMUD.
I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION. SUPERVISOR CHEN IS EXCUSED.
MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE ITEMS ON
ITEMS 28 THROUGH 31 SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY
DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD
MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EITHER
ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTIONS ARE APPROVED.
AND WITH THAT LET'S GO TO ROLL CALL.
THE FIRST MEMBER UP TO INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS IS
SUPERVISOR CHAN SUBMIT THANK YOU SUPER VISOR CHIN ROLL CALL
FOR INTRODUCTIONS WE HAVE SIX MINUTES UNTIL 230 THANK YOU
MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES, I AM INTRODUCING
OUR RESOLUTION TODAY TO SUPPORT STATE SENATOR BILL NIGHT FOR
FOUR INTRODUCED BY SENATOR SCOTT WEINER WHICH WOULD MAKE
ACUPUNCTURE A COVERT BENEFIT UNDER MEDICAL THIS WOULD ALLOW
IMMIGRANTS MEDICAL RECIPIENT TO ACCESS CULTURALLY APPROPRIATE
TREATMENT. >> ABOUT 10% OF OUR PATIENTS
UTILIZE MEDI-CAL TO PAY FOR ACUPUNCTURE SERVICES.
>> ACCESS WILL ALSO SERVE WOMEN'S REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH FOR
WOMEN EXPERIENCING SYMPTOMS OF PRE PREMENSTRUAL SYMPTOMS
AND MENTAL POS ACUPUNCTURE AS AN ALTERNATIVE ROLE FOR
ALLEVIATING SYMPTOMS STANDARDIZING ACUPUNCTURE AS A
COVER SERVICES UNDER MEDI-CAL WILL BE BENEFICIAL FOR MANY
IN OUR COMMUNITY. THANK YOU FOR SUPERVISOR CHEN
FOR YOUR EARLY CO SPONSORSHIPS. >> I ALSO HAVE ANOTHER
RESOLUTIONS. I AM ALSO INTRODUCING OUR
RESOLUTION TODAY IN SUPPORT OF ASSEMBLYMEMBER MAHANEY SPILL A
AB TWO FIVE PHI WHICH WILL DESIGNATE MAY 17TH OF EACH YEAR
AS BRUCE LEE DAY BRUCE LEE WAS BORN IN THE CHINESE HOSPITAL
AND HIS EARLY FAMILY HISTORY ARE DEEPLY CONNECTED TO SAN
FRANCISCO'S CHINATOWN AND HIS CHINESE PERFORMING ARTS.
HIS PARENTS TAUGHT WITH THE PERFORMING ARTS COMMUNITY
DURING AN ERA IN WHICH ASIAN AMERICAN AND IMMIGRANTS FACED
PERSISTENT DISCRIMINATION AND EXCLUSIONS.
BRUCE LEE WAS MORE THAN A MARTIAL ARTIST, A FILM ICON HIS
SHATTER STEREOTYPES AND REDEFINE WHAT WAS POSSIBLE
FOR ASIAN-AMERICANS HIS LEGACY EXTENDS FAR BEYOND THE SCREEN.
HE CHANGED HOW THE WORLD SEES US AND HOW WE SEE OURSELVES.
>> REPRESENTATION MATTERS AND IN HIS CONTRIBUTION SHAPE
THE FABRIC OF THE CITY AND THIS NATION.
ON BRUCE LEE DAY PUBLIC SCHOOLS WILL BE ENCOURAGED TO TEACH
STUDENTS THIS HISTORY SO THAT WE MAY CONTINUE TO CARRY
FORWARD BRUCE LEE'S SPIRIT AND TO BE COURAGEOUS
AND UNAPOLOGETICALLY BOW THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN ALSO FOR
YOUR EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN
SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
>> COLLEAGUES, I'M GOING TO PROVIDE SOME UPDATES FROM
OUTSIDE BOARDS AND COMMISSIONS THAT SHOULD TAKE US TO 230 AT
THE BAY CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT COMMISSION OR
BCCDC. WE ARE INVESTING IN NEW
TECHNOLOGY TO MODERNIZE AND SUPPORT BCCDC SCE PLANNING
AND REGULATORY PROGRAMS. THIS IS A MUCH NEEDED UPDATE TO
IMPROVE THE APPLICATION PROCESS AND PROVIDE FOR MORE
INFORMATION AND TRANSPARENCY TO MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC.
WE RECENTLY RECEIVED AN UPDATE ON THE STATE OF OUR ESTUARY
AND A BRIEFING ON OUR PROGRESS ON THE REGIONAL SHORELINE
ADAPTATION PLAN PROGRESS. THE AGENCY IS CONTINUING TO
ENGAGE IN ROBUST COMMUNITY OUTREACH ON THE PLAN AND WOULD
WELCOME THE OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK WITH ANY OF YOUR
RESPECTIVE COMMUNITY GROUPS COLLEAGUES WHO ARE INTERESTED
IN THE TOPIC. WE'VE HEARD ENFORCEMENT
DECISIONS INCLUDING ONE THAT WAS SUCCESSFULLY RESOLVED
AND WILL HELP AN EXCITING PROJECT IN MY DISTRICT
IN MISSION CREEK TO MOVE FORWARD SO I AM HAPPY TO THANK
STAFF FOR THAT AND FOR THE ASSOCIATION OF BAY AREA
GOVERNMENTS OR A BAG. I LOOK FORWARD TO WELCOMING
SUPERVISOR CHEN TO THE SAN FRANCISCO DELEGATION TO THAT
AUGUST BODY AT OUR MOST RECENT MEETING WE MADE NOMINATIONS TO
THE INAUGURAL MTS A BAG COMMUNITY ADVISORY COUNCIL.
I THANK NEW MEMBERS FOR THEIR WILLINGNESS TO SERVE IN THAT
ROLE. WE ALSO PASSED THE 2026 MTC A
BAG JOINTED ADVOCACY PROGRAM WITH THE FOLLOWING PRIORITIES
AT THE STATE LEVEL FOR THE YEAR ONE TRANSPORTATION FUNDING TO
HOUSING FUNDING AND HOUSING SUPPORTIVE SERVICES
AND POLICIES THREE PURSUING A NEW ROUND OF REGIONAL EARLY
ACTION PLANNING GRANTS FOR SB 375 MODERNIZATION FIVE
MONITORING PROPOSALS AND ENGAGING IN DISCUSSIONS
RELATED TO RINA THE REGIONAL HOUSING NEEDS ALLOCATION
TRANSPORTATION SYSTEM EFFECTIVENESS IMPROVING THE
TRANSIT RIDER EXPERIENCE TRANSPORTATION PROJECT DELIVERY
AND CLIMATE RESILIENCE AND ENVIRONMENT AND FINALLY THE
PLANNED BAY AREA 2050 PLUS IMPLEMENTATION.
OUR FEDERAL PRIORITIES ARE SIMILAR WITH A FOCUS ON TRANSIT
AND HOUSING FUNDING, SURFACE TRANSPORTATION REAUTHORIZATION
AND CLIMATE RESILIENCE AND ENVIRONMENT ON THE HEALTH
SERVICE SYSTEM WHICH I ALSO SERVE ON.
I WANTED TO PROVIDE A BRIEF UPDATE FROM OUR MOST RECENT
MEETING WHICH WAS ON FEBRUARY 12TH.
OVERALL, THE HEALTH SERVICE SYSTEM REMAINS IN GOOD STANDING
WITH NO MAJOR AUDIT FINDINGS. ROUTINE AUDITS ARE ONGOING
AND SEVERAL MAJOR BENEFIT CONTRACTS ARE CURRENTLY OUT TO
BID. THE SYSTEM CONTINUES TO FACE
PRESSURE FROM RISING HEALTH CARE COSTS.
THIS IS A NATIONAL PHENOMENON. THE TRUST FUND IS PROJECTED TO
DECLINE DUE TO HIGHER MEDICAL CLAIMS WHILE THE HEALTH CARE
SUSTAINABILITY FUND REMAINS RELATIVELY STABLE.
NATIONAL TRENDS SHOW HEALTH CARE COSTS RISING FROM 9 TO 10%
ANNUALLY WHICH WILL INFORM FUTURE RATE DECISIONS.
AND I'M SURE THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WE WILL BE GRAPPLING WITH
AT BUDGET TIME. I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE
RECENT CONCERNS ABOUT COVERAGE DENIALS INCLUDING FOR
FIREFIGHTERS AND CANCER PATIENTS.
THESE ISSUES REALLY HIGHLIGHT THE NEED FOR CONTINUED
OVERSIGHT AND ACCOUNTABILITY. I WILL CONTINUE WORKING WITH
THE HEALTH SERVICE SYSTEM ON THAT AND I WANT TO EXPRESS A
SINGLE OUT FOR GRATITUDE BUDGET CHAIR CONNIE CHEN WHO HAS BEEN
MY PARTNER IN THIS. THE BOARD ALSO REVIEWED OVER
THE NEXT TWO YEARS OF PROPOSED BUDGETS WHICH MAINTAIN CORE
SERVICES WHILE IDENTIFYING TARGETED SAVINGS.
IN ADDITION, WE APPROVED SEVERAL ITEMS TO MAINTAIN
STABILITY FOR MEMBERS INCLUDING NO INCREASE TO BASIC VISION
RATES. SO THAT'S GOOD NEWS AND FLAT
RATES FOR LIFE AND DISABILITY COVERAGE FOR 2027.
AND FINALLY THE SYSTEM CONTINUES TO FOCUS ON MEMBER
SERVICES WITH STRONG DEMAND FOR THE EMPLOYEE ASSISTANCE PROGRAM
AND ONGOING EFFORTS TO IMPROVE CALL CENTER PERFORMANCE
AND COMMUNICATIONS. AND THAT'S IT FOR MY OUTSIDE
BOARDS AND COMMISSIONS AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY SUPERVISOR FIELDER WE'LL GO ONE
MORE. >> MADAM CLERK, I HAVE AN
IN MEMORIAM AND I'M WAITING FOR THE FAMILY TO ARRIVE.
>> COULD WE PLEASE BE REFERRED BACK TO ME?
>> CERTAINLY. ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> ONE MORE. BOTH SAY ONE MORE.
OKAY. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. ON MR. PRESIDENT.
>> OH, MY GOODNESS. I REALLY WANT TO TURN TO 230.
>> WELL, IT JUST ALL RIGHT, I'LL DO A FEW COLLEAGUES.
>> I HAVE A COUPLE OF ITEMS. WELL, FIRST I'M INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION OF SUPPORT FOR STATE SENATOR WEINER'S SB 875
LEGISLATION TO REMOVE SPECIAL PRIVILEGES THAT INVESTOR OWNED
UTILITIES LIKE P, G AND E HAVE UNDER CURRENT LAW.
THIS LEGISLATION WILL MAKE IT EASIER FOR CITIES LIKE SAN
FRANCISCO TO ENSURE THAT THEY THAT THEIR RESIDENTS HAVE
ACCESS TO AFFORDABLE CLEAN AND RENEWABLE ENERGY THROUGH A
PUBLIC POWER PROGRAM. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISORS
DORSEY, MAHMOOD SADR AND MELGAR FOR THEIR CO-SPONSOR SCHIP
AND I HOPE WE WILL HAVE UNANIMOUS SUPPORT WHEN WE
CONSIDER THIS NEXT WEEK. I HAVE AN UPDATE FROM MY
OUTSIDE SERVICE AS VICE CHAIR OF JPA OVER THERE WE'RE HELPING
TO OVERSEE THE AGENCY'S OPERATIONS AT THE SALESFORCE
TRANSIT CENTER AND PROGRESS AND DEVELOPING THE PORTAL
IN 2025 THE TGA MADE PROGRESS ON THE PORTAL.
WE DISCUSSED THIS AT THE TA RECENTLY BUT BY DEVELOPING
AND ISSUING A REQUEST FOR PROPOSALS FOR MAJOR CIVIL
TUNNEL WORK FOR THE PORTAL, THE TGP SUCCESSFULLY ADVOCATED FOR
EXTENSION OF THE STATE'S CAP AND TRADE BILL THROUGH 2045
WHICH WILL ENABLE TGP TO APPLY FOR $500 MILLION IN GRANTS WE
SECURED OR THE TGA SECURED AMENDMENTS TO THE MTC'S MAJOR
PROJECT ADVANCEMENT POLICY TO ADVANCE THE PORTAL AS THE
REGION'S NEXT MAJOR RAIL EXTENSION AND ADVANCED THE
RIGHT OF WAY ACQUISITION AND UTILITY RELOCATION AS PART
OF THE PORTAL'S PRE-CONSTRUCTION
PRE-CONSTRUCTION PROGRAM. SO THEY'VE BEEN VERY BUSY
AND WE BELIEVE WE ARE ON TRACK TO SECURE THE $3.4 BILLION FTA
CAPITAL INVESTMENT GRANT THAT WAS COMMITTED TO THE PROJECT
UNDER THE BIDEN ADMINISTRATION ONCE WE SECURE THE LOCAL
MATCHING FUNDS AND THIS YEAR THE TGA WILL CONTINUE TO FOCUS
ON FUNDING DESIGN DEVELOPMENT, PROCUREMENT RIGHT OF WAY
AND ENABLING WORKS. LASTLY, I HAVE AN IN MEMORIAM
FOR WAYNE JASMINE WHO DIED ON JANUARY 28TH 2026.
WAYNE WAS A LONG TIME HIV AIDS SURVIVOR AND ADVOCATE AND A
LEADER IN THE CANNABIS MOVEMENT.
HE ARRIVED IN SAN FRANCISCO IN 1993 LOOKING TO FIND A
COMMUNITY AND FAMILY IN SAN FRANCISCO AS HIV POSITIVE LGBTQ
PLUS COMMUNITY. HE BECAME A VOLUNTEER WITH THE
SAN FRANCISCO CANNABIS BUYERS CLUB WHERE HE JOINED THE FIGHT
TO BRING CANNABIS TO THOSE SUFFERING FROM AIDS.
HE VOLUNTEERED AS A DOORMAN AT THE CLUB WHERE HE BALANCED
CONTROLLING ACCESS WITH GETTING PEOPLE WHO WERE IN SERIOUS NEED
OF HELP INSIDE THE ORIGINAL CLUB LOCATION WAS NOT ADA
ACCESSIBLE SO WAYNE AND OTHERS WOULD HOIST WHEELCHAIR USERS UP
THE STAIRCASE FOR MANY PEOPLE WAYNE WAS THE FIRST PERSON THEY
WOULD MEET WHEN THEY ARRIVED AT THE CLUB.
MANY CAME IN NERVOUS WITH A DOCTOR'S NOTE IN HAND AND WAYNE
WELCOMED THEM IN AND GUIDED THEM THROUGH THE INTAKE
PROCESS. EVENTUALLY THE CANNABIS BUYERS
CLUB STARTED THE SMALL POT FARM IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA OPERATED
BY A NUMBER OF CRITICALLY ILL PATIENTS.
WAYNE RAN FARM OPERATIONS WITH THE OTHER ADVOCATES BUILDING
COMMUNITY AND COURAGEOUSLY STANDING UP AGAINST RAIDS AFTER
PROP 215 PASSED IN 1996, WAYNE BECAME THE FIRST PATIENT TO
SIGN UP WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH
WHEN IT ROLLED OUT ITS CANNABIS PATIENT IDENTIFICATION SYSTEM
GIVING AWAY IN THE TITLE OF PATIENT NUMBER ONE.
IN HIS LATER YEARS HE OPENED UP A SMALL CANNABIS DISPENSARY A
DISPENSARY ON TO VISIT STREET ALONG WITH CLOSE FRIENDS WHO
WORKED IN THE MOVEMENT. >> HIS SAID PASSED HIS SUDDEN
PASSING IS A PROFOUND LOSS TO ALL WHO KNEW HIM AND TO THE
MOVEMENT HE HELPED CREATE AT A CRITICAL AND TRYING TIME
IN HISTORY, WAYNE ROSE TO THE OCCASION STANDING UP TO
POWERFUL FORCES TO HELP PEOPLE IN PAIN.
ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS IN THE CITY
AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO, WE WANT TO EXTEND OUR DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO HIS MANY COLLEAGUES AND COUNTLESS
FRIENDS. HIS LEGACY WILL LIVE ON IN BOTH
THE INDUSTRY HE HELPED BUILD AND THE COMMUNITY HE INSPIRED.
REST IN POWER WAYNE DRUMMOND MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING
AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
AND NOW I THINK WE CAN GO TO OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER.
>> YES, THE 230 SPECIAL ORDER IS THE RECOGNITION OF
COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> AND TODAY WE WILL START WITH
DISTRICT TEN SUPERVISOR SHERMAN WALTON.
>> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MADAM AND COLLEAGUES.
>> TODAY WE ARE HONORING BETTER ZIP GUNS DOWN ROSHAD IF YOU
COULD COME UP TO THE PODIUM I AM PROUD TO RECOGNIZE THE
INCREDIBLE COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP BEHIND BATTER'S UP GUNS DOWN
THE WHOLE MOVEMENT WHICH BEGAN IN APRIL 2020 FIRST AS A SIMPLE
IDEA A FACEBOOK POST INVITING PEOPLE TO COME TOGETHER FOR A
SUNDAY SOFTBALL GAME AT GILLMAN PARK HAS GROWN INTO SOMETHING
MUCH MORE POWERFUL A MOVEMENT THAT BRINGS NEIGHBORHOODS
TOGETHER, BUILDS RELATIONSHIPS ACROSS CITIES AND CREATES SAFE
POSITIVE SPACES FOR OUR COMMUNITY UNDER THE LEADERSHIP
OF ROSANNE DESPERATELY AND RANDY TAYLOR HEART CITY
PRESCHOOL TURN THAT VISION INTO ACTION.
WHAT STARTED AS ONE TEAM QUICKLY GREW INTO MULTIPLE
TEAMS AND REGULAR COMMUNITY GAMES THAT NOW WELCOME PLAYERS
AND FAMILIES FROM ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO GO OAKLAND.
RICHMOND EAST PALO ALTO, REDWOOD CITY, SAN BRUNO
AND BEYOND. THESE GATHERINGS ARE ABOUT MORE
THAN SOFTBALL. THEY'RE ABOUT CONNECTION,
HEALING AND REMINDING US THAT WE ARE STRONGER WHEN WE COME
TOGETHER AS ONE COMMUNITY IS UP.
GUNS DOWN REPRESENTS THE BELIEF THAT PREVENTION STARTS WITH
OPPORTUNITY BY CREATING A SPACE WHERE PEOPLE OF ALL AGES CAN
COME TOGETHER, COMPETE, LAUGH AND SUPPORT ONE ANOTHER.
THIS MOVEMENT IS HELPING PROVIDE ALTERNATIVES FOR YOUTH
AND MENTORSHIP FOR THE NEXT GENERATION.
>> IT SHOWS THAT SOMETHING AS SIMPLE AS A GAME CAN BUILD
TRUST, FOSTER LEADERSHIP AND OPEN DOORS FOR YOUNG PEOPLE
WHO NEED POSITIVE OUTLETS AND GUIDANCE.
THEIR WORK ALSO REMINDS US THAT VIOLENCE PREVENTION IS NOT JUST
ABOUT POLICY IT IS ABOUT PEOPLE ,RELATIONSHIPS AND COMMUNITY.
IT IS ABOUT SHOWING UP CONSISTENTLY CREATING SAFE
ENVIRONMENTS AND INVESTING IN PROGRAMS THAT UPLIFT OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS THROUGH SOFTBALL MENTORSHIP AND COMMUNITY
ENGAGEMENT BATTER'S UP GUNS DOWN IS HOW IS HELPING SHAPE A
FUTURE WHERE OUR YOUTH FEEL SUPPORTED, VALUED AND INSPIRED.
SO TODAY WE RECOGNIZE THE BATTER'S UP GUNS DOWN MOVEMENT
FOR THEIR COMMITMENT TO BRINGING COMMUNITIES TOGETHER,
PROVIDING POSITIVE OPPORTUNITIES FOR YOUTH
AND WORKING EVERY DAY TOWARDS SAFER NEIGHBORHOODS
AND BRIGHTER FUTURES FOR US ALL THANK YOU FOR LEADING WITH
HEART AND FOR BUILDING COMMUNITY AND FOR PROVING THAT
WHEN WE COME TOGETHER GREAT THINGS HAPPEN.
>> THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR WALTON LOOK LIKE HE SAID THIS ACTUALLY
STARTED AS JUST A PICK UP TYPE GAME MEETING AT THE COMMUNITY
PARK LOCAL COMMUNITY BUT IT QUICKLY EXPANDED TO A LARGER,
LARGER LARGER FOCUS WHEN WE STARTED CONNECTING WITH CITIES
FROM OAKLAND, ALL PARTS OF OAKLAND EAST WEST.
NORTH OAKLAND, EAST PALO ALTO, REDWOOD CITY, SAN BRUNO WE EVEN
HAD GUYS EVEN COME DOWN FROM SACRAMENTO BUT TWO SUPERVISORS
AT ONE POINT IT REALLY STARTED OUT AS A COMMUNITY THING.
I'M 46 YEARS OLD, GREW UP IN THE BAYVIEW.
HUNDREDS POINT ALL MY LIFE AND WE HAD A LOT OF VIOLENCE
IN THE PAST SO IT CAME AS A DIFFERENT AVENUE OF TRYING TO
PREVENT VIOLENCE SO WHAT SUPERVISOR WALTON AND PERCY CAN
TELL YOU THE GUYS THAT WE HAVE OUT THERE AND THE YOUTH THAT WE
HAVE OUT THERE AT ONE POINT COULDN'T STAND ON THE SAME
STREET CORNER OR BE IN THE SAME VICINITY AT THE SAME TIME.
SO WE JUST TOOK A DIFFERENT AVENUE USING SPORTS
AND SOFTBALL IS NOT A CONTACT SPORT SO THAT HELPS A LOT A
HOME WE WOULD WANT TO DO FOOTBALL AS A AS A WAY TO GET
IT GOING. SO SOFTBALL HELPS A LOT BECAUSE
WE ARE ON OPPOSITE SIDES OF THE HILL.
>> THE BIGGEST THING HITS YOU IS A SOFTBALL.
THAT HURTS TOO. BUT IT REALLY WORKED OUT
AND YOU KNOW, LIKE I SAID, WE STARTED WITH ONE TEAM THEN WE
HAD ONE LADIES TEAM AND THEN IT JUST QUICKLY EXPANDED AS FOLKS
START SEEING THE COMMUNITY COME TOGETHER IN THE COMMUNITY PARK
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD IN THE ROUGH NEIGHBORHOOD THAT SOME
FOLKS MIGHT CONSIDER AND IT JUST BECAME BIGGER THAN WHAT WE
ACTUALLY THOUGHT IT WOULD BE AND WE'RE GOING ON YEAR NUMBER
FIVE THIS YEAR WILL BE STARTING THE SEASON IN ABOUT TWO WEEKS
MARCH 15TH EVERY SUNDAY AT GILMAN PARK.
AND AGAIN IT'S REALLY ABOUT BRINGING THE WHOLE COMMUNITY
AND OTHER CITIES TO OUR PARK TO HAVE A GOOD TIME AND SHOW
EVERYONE THAT WE CAN GET ALONG AND WORK TOGETHER.
SO THANK YOU AGAIN SUPERVISOR WALDEN TOTALLY UNEXPECTED.
I WAS NEVER LOOKING FOR RECOGNITION WHEN WE STARTED
THIS PROGRAM BUT I TOTALLY APPRECIATE YOU BEING A BIG
SUPPORTER ALWAYS COME ON DOWN TO THE PARK AND SHOWING YOUR
FACE AND SUPPORTING THE MOVEMENT BUT NEVER NEVER WAS
LOOKING FOR THIS TYPE OF SCENERY OR THIS ATTENTION.
BUT OUR APPRECIATE IT. >> THANK YOU GUYS.
AND NOW I WANT TO INVITE DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISORS
SUPERVISOR JEN THANK YOU PRESIDENT MENDOZA
AND COLLEAGUES HAPPY LUNAR NEW YEAR AND HAPPY BLACK HISTORY
MONTH TODAY I'M EXCITED TO RECOGNIZE A TRUE GEM
AND LONGSTANDING BLACK OWNED BUSINESS THAT HAS BEEN
OPERATING IN THE RICHMOND SINCE 1978.
NOW THIS IS THE INTERESTING PART THEY ARE NOT HERE TODAY
IN THE CHAMBER BECAUSE THEY ARE IN THEIR SHOP AND IT'S HOW
AMAZING THEY ARE. THE HUSBAND AND WIFE DUO JAMES
AND JIM ROSS, JIM ROSS AND THEY ARE THE JUST AMAZING BUSINESS
OWNER IN THE RICHMOND AND I KNOW THAT THEY'RE ALSO A LITTLE
BIT OLDER AND THEY REALLY ENJOY THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
JIM AND JAMES PROVIDE QUALITY WORKMANSHIP THAT IS INCREDIBLY
RARE IN SAN FRANCISCO SO AND THEY PROVIDE AN HONEST,
RELIABLE AND AFFORDABLE SERVICE THAT IS INCREDIBLY VALUABLE
SERVICE FOR OUR NEIGHBORS THAT IS KNOWN AS THE JAY AND OUR
UPHOLSTERY ANCHORS BUSINESS IN OUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
SO IN MY OPINION THEIR BUSINESS AND THEIR REPAIR SKILLS
AND CRAFTSMANSHIP IS AMONG THE BEST IN OUR REGION.
THEY HAVE EARNED THE TRUST AND GLOWING RECOMMENDATION FROM
SO MANY RESIDENTS AND CUSTOMERS BECAUSE OF THEIR UNPARALLELED
EXPERIENCE, CARE AND DEDICATION AND THEY TRULY ARE THE FABRIC
OF THE RICHMOND DISTRICT. THE SHOP AND WORKSHOP IS FILLED
WITH ARRAY OF FABRIC SAMPLES, CUSHIONS, MATERIALS, EQUIPMENT
AND ALL THE ESSENTIAL THAT MAGICALLY REPAIR AND TRANSFORM
ANY PIECE OF FURNITURE. THEIR WORK AND ATTENTION TO
DETAIL TRULY EXEMPLIFIES THE ART OF CRAFTSMANSHIP THAT IS
MADE TO LAST. I REALLY APPRECIATE THEM BOTH
AND I THINK THAT WHAT WE ARE GOING TO DO IS THAT WE WILL
BRING THE PRESENTATION AND THE HONOR TO THEM IN THE
NEIGHBORHOOD TO IT AT THEIR SHOP SO THAT WE CAN BRING THE
COMMUNITY TO CELEBRATE THEM IN THE RICHMOND TOGETHER ALONG
WITH BALBOA VILLAGE AND OTHER MERCHANTS THAT WILL THEN BE
ABLE TO CELEBRATE THEM AT THEIR SPACE.
SO I JUST WANTED TO THANK THEM TO TAKE THIS OPPORTUNITY IN THE
CHAMBER FOR THEIR COMMITMENT BUT MOST IMPORTANTLY FOR THEIR
LOVE FOR THE RICHMOND AND THEY'RE LOCATED AT 3 TO 3
ONE BALBOA STREETS BETWEEN 33RD AND 34TH AVENUE.
SO WE ARE ALL GOING TO BE THERE ONE OF THESE DAYS ALONG WITH
ALL THEIR NEIGHBORS AND CUSTOMERS SO WE CAN SELL IT
TO CELEBRATE THEM IN THEIR SHOP AND THEIR SPACE.
>> THANK YOU AND THANK THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN.
AND NEXT UP I WOULD LIKE TO THANK SUPERVISOR CHERYL FOR
TAKING CARE OF ONE OF MY CONSTITUENTS WHEN I HAD MANAGED
TO GET MYSELF OVERBOOKED TODAY BUT THIS WAS AN IMPORTANT ONE
TO DO SO THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHERYL WELL COLLEAGUES, I GOT
TO TELL YOU IT'S NOT THAT HEAVY OF A LIFT.
PRESIDENT MANDELL MEAN WHEN I GET THE HONOR OF COMMENDING A
GUY LIKE HIS MORRIS SO WOULD YOU PLEASE COME FORWARD TO THE
PODIUM HERE SO PRESENT GENTLEMAN YOU MAY NOT KNOW THIS
BUT WE'VE ACTUALLY GOTTEN THE CHANCE TO WORK TOGETHER SO THIS
IS REALLY NOT THAT BIG A DEAL FOR ME.
IT'S ACTUALLY A GREAT DEAL BUT MOSTLY I THINK FROM ALL OF US
WE WANT TO SAY THANK YOU TO YOU.
>> HE'S THIS MOORE HAS LED A LENGTHY CAREER OF PUBLIC
SERVICE CULMINATING WITH HIS INCREDIBLY DISAPPOINTING,
SADDENING, MADDENING BUT WELL-DESERVED RETIREMENT AS
CHIEF INFORMATION OFFICER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT, HE JUST RETIRED ON DECEMBER 31ST AFTER 20 YEARS
LEADING THE FIRE DEPARTMENT'S PUBLIC SAFETY TECHNOLOGY
INNOVATION. AND YOU ARE AS I THINK YOU KNOW
AND I HOPE YOU KNOW, WIDELY RESPECTED DUE TO YOUR WORK
ETHIC INTELLIGENCE AND WILLINGNESS TO HELP OTHERS.
BORN IN VENEZUELA, HIS WIFE'S OBTAINED HIS DEGREE IN CIVIL
ENGINEERING THERE BEFORE MOVING TO THE UNITED STATES TO OBTAIN
HIS PH.D. IN STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING AT UC BERKELEY.
>> HIS FIRST FULL TIME EMPLOYMENT WITH THE CITY BEGAN
ON SEPTEMBER 10TH, 2001 WHEN HE WAS HIRED BY THE DEPARTMENT OF
TECHNOLOGY AS AN ENGINEER AND PROJECT MANAGER.
PRIOR TO THIS ROLE HE WORKED AS A CONTRACTOR FOR THE DEPARTMENT
OF TECHNOLOGY ON THE CITY'S COMPUTER AIDED DISPATCH
REPLACEMENT PROJECT. NOW FOLLOWING HIS WORK IN THE
SUCCESSFUL COMPLETION OF THE CAD PROJECT, HIS USE WAS
IDENTIFIED AS THE BEST PERSON TO UPGRADE THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT'S TECHNOLOGY PROFILE BASED ON HIS PREVIOUS WORK
ASSISTING THEN FIRE CHIEF JOIN HIS WHITE.
AND IN DECEMBER OF 2004 HE JUST BEGAN AN EXCEPTIONAL 20 PLUS
YEAR CAREER WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT.
AND DURING THAT TIME HE OVERSAW NUMEROUS PROJECTS DIRECTLY
CONTRIBUTED TO OPERATIONAL ADMINISTRATIVE FISCAL
EFFICIENCIES. HE WAS INVOLVED IN EVERY ASPECT
OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND THROUGHOUT HIS CAREER HE
HAD A UNIQUE ABILITY TO FIND A SOLUTION TO ANY PROBLEM EVEN IF
THAT MEANT BUILDING IT HIMSELF. >> EVEN ON CHRISTMAS MORNING
WHEN SAN FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT'S COMPUTERS CRASHED
HE CAME IN TO FIX IT HIMSELF. HE DEVELOPED A CUSTOM
TECHNOLOGY INFRASTRUCTURE THAT THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT STILL RELIES ON TO THIS DAY IS ITS BACKBONE.
HE CREATED SOLUTIONS FOR SCHEDULING PAYROLL INVENTORY
INSPECTIONS AND MORE. THESE SOLUTIONS RESULTED
IN SIGNIFICANT ANNUAL SAVINGS FOR THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND FOR
THE ENTIRE CITY. AND YOUR COMMITMENT AS A PUBLIC
SERVANT HAS EXTENDED BEYOND THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
YOU'VE COLLABORATED WITH COUNTLESS DEPARTMENTS ACROSS
THE CITY INCLUDING PUBLIC SAFETY PARTNERS AND THE
COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE AND I PERSONALLY BENEFITED FROM HIS
USES INNOVATIVE COLLABORATIVE SPIRIT WHEN WE WORKED TOGETHER
TO BUILD THIS NATION'S FIRST DATABASE INTEGRATING HOMELESS
PUBLIC HEALTH AND EMERGENCY RESPONSE DATA FOR PEOPLE
SUFFERING ON OUR STREETS CALLED ASTRID.
THIS I WANT TO THANK YOU PERSONALLY FOR YOUR DEDICATION
,FOR YOUR PASSION AND FOR YOUR DEEP CONTRIBUTIONS IN MAKING
SAN FRANCISCO SAFE THROUGHOUT YOUR INCREDIBLE CAREER.
WE WISH YOU ALL THE BEST IN YOUR RETIREMENT.
>> THANK YOU. AND BEFORE YOU SPEAK, I WANT TO
SAY I WANT TO CONGRATULATE YOU. I'VE KNOWN LAZARUS I THINK
PROBABLY FOR LIKE IT'S GOT TO BE MAYBE 20 YEARS OR SO.
JESUS IS LIKE ME A BIG GAY AND WE BOTH ARE BIG GAY RUNNERS
AND SO WE BOTH ARE OUR SAN FRANCISCO FRONT RUNNERS.
BUT HE'S ALSO NOW REGULARLY KICKS MY IN VARIOUS CLASSES.
AND SO THAT'S YOU KNOW THAT'S THAT'S SORT OF AND SO WHAT I
LEARNED THAT YOU WORKED FOR THE FIRE DEPARTMENT SOMETIME IN THE
LAST YEAR OR TWO THAT WAS THAT THAT WAS AN ADDED BONUS TO KNOW
THAT YOU'RE DOING ALL THIS GOOD WORK FOR THE CITY.
YOU ALSO HAVE A COUPLE OF CHIEFS HERE.
>> WE HAVE JOEY ON HIS WAY BACK THERE AND WE ALSO HAVE DEAN
CRESPIN AND I THINK AT LEAST I MEAN EITHER I KNOW I THINK
CHIEF CHRISTMAN DID WANT TO SAY A FEW WORDS AT LEAST THIS IS
WHAT I'VE HEARD. I COULD BE WRONG.
AND IF AND IF CHIEF IS RIGHT, IF YOU WANT TO SAY ANYTHING,
YOU SHOULD COME UP AS WELL. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. I HAD THE UNFORTUNATE LUCK OF
HAVING TO BE THE PERSON THAT HAD TO SAY GOODBYE TO JESUS
IN THE LAST YEAR AND I SAW AN INCREDIBLE TRANSFORMATION
IN HIM AND THE ONE YEAR THAT WE WERE ABLE TO WORK TOGETHER
AND ONE WAS THAT ONE THAT I'VE SEEN MANY TIMES WHEN MEMBERS OF
OUR DEPARTMENT OR OTHER DEPARTMENTS RETIRE.
THERE'S THAT APPREHENSIVE FEELING OF RETIREMENT
AND APPREHENSION. THE FIRST SIX MONTHS I THINK HE
KNEW HE WAS GOING TO RETIRE BUT HE STRUGGLED WITH IT.
HE BATTLED WITH IT AND I THINK HE REALLY WAS CONCERNED ABOUT
WHAT THE LEGACY WOULD BE AND OF COURSE HOW THINGS WOULD MOVE ON
WITHOUT HIM. AND I THINK THE FACT THAT WE
BROUGHT RON DIBIASE ON BOARD AND THE FACT THAT WE HAVE A
FANTASTIC IT STAFF MADE HIM COMFORTABLE AND AT PEACE WITH
HIS DECISION AND I'D LIKE TO SAY THIS TO YOU, MR. MORA I
THINK A LOT OF THE MEMBERS OF UNIFORM GET A LOT OF CREDIT FOR
A LOT OF THE THINGS WE DO IN THE FIELD.
BUT THIS GENTLEMAN DESERVES AN EQUAL AMOUNT OF CREDIT FOR THE
FIRE IS GOING OUT. THE FOLKS GETTING RESCUED
AND HE REALLY DESERVES ALL THE ACCOLADES THAT HE GET THAT HE'S
GETTING AND WE HOPE HIM WISH HIM A SAFE AND HAPPY RETIREMENT
AND CHIEF, HIS WIFE IS GOING TO COME ON UP AS WELL AND THEN
WE'RE GONNA HEAR FROM HIS SERVICE AND THEN WE'LL DO OUR
PHOTO. GOOD AFTERNOON, SUPERVISORS.
IT'S NICE TO BE VISITING BACK IN THE CHAMBERS.
>> I DON'T MISS ALL THE TIME THAT I SPENT HERE THAT MUCH BUT
I THANK YOU FOR WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND CERTAINLY SUPERVISOR
MANDOLIN AND ALL OF YOUR COLLEAGUES JUST BRIEFLY WANT TO
SAY I'M VERY PROUD OF THE MAN WHO STANDS BEHIND ME.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR ACKNOWLEDGING HIM.
I HAD THE GOOD FORTUNE OF HIRING HIS HOUSE IN DECEMBER OF
2004 AND WE HAD WORKED TOGETHER WHEN YOU WERE A CONTRACT
EMPLOYEE AND I SAID TO MYSELF I'VE GOT TO GET HIM FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT AND LIKE THE CHIEF SAID, HE'S
REALLY AN UNSUNG HERO. I'VE HAD THE GOOD FORTUNE OF
HIRING OVER 100 PEOPLE IN THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT,
FINE MEN AND WOMEN. HE'S WHO STANDS UP AMONGST THE
FIRST TOP TEN I WOULD SAY OF MY HIRES.
HE IS ONE OF THE MOST INTELLIGENT, KINDEST, MOST
HUMBLE HUMAN BEINGS I'VE EVER MET.
AND NOT ONLY WAS HE A BELOVED TEAM MEMBER OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT BUT HAS BECOME A VERY CLOSE FRIEND
OF MINE AND I WISH YOU WELL AND WE'LL GET TOGETHER MORE NOW
THAT WE'RE BOTH RETIRED. CONGRATULATION.
>> THANK YOU AND GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
>> IF I MAY JUST BRIEFLY A FEW COMMENTS.
MARK CORSO FINANCE AND PLANNING AT THE FIRE DEPARTMENT IT IS AN
HONOR HERE TO BE HERE TODAY ON TO RECOGNIZE HEY SUZ HE'S BEEN
JUST AN INCREDIBLE STEWARD FOR THE CITY I JUST ON A PERSONAL
LEVEL HE'S BECOME A GREAT FRIEND OVER THE YEARS.
HE'S ALWAYS BEEN SOMEONE TO BOUNCE IDEAS OFF OF AS NO
OFFENSE TO ANYBODY IN UNIFORM HERE BUT BEING A CIVILIAN IN A
UNIFORM DEPARTMENT CAN BE CHALLENGING AT TIMES AND SO
HAVING SOMEBODY IN THAT SIMILAR EXPERIENCE TO TALK TO YOU HAS
ALWAYS BEEN A GREAT RESOURCE BUT GREAT FRIEND AND I THINK
ONE OF THE KEY POINTS TO AND HE'LL TELL YOU THIS AS WELL
WHATEVER HE DID HE DID SO MUCH FOR THE DEPARTMENT BUT WHENEVER
HE DID ANYTHING HE WAS ALWAYS THINKING WHAT IS THE BEST FOR
THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO AND FOR THE CITY AND THAT IS
JUST DESERVES THE UTMOST RESPECT, A WONDERFUL CAREER.
>> SO CONGRATULATIONS. THIS IS THANK YOU SUPERVISOR
CARROLL AND THANK YOU THE BOARD CAN YOU PULL THAT MICROPHONE
DOWN THERE? >> I WANT TO HEAR YOU WELL
AND THANK YOU THE BOARD FOR THIS HONOR.
THE REALITY IS THAT I ALWAYS FELT IT WAS AND IT WAS AN
INCREDIBLE PRIVILEGE TO WORK FOR THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
I TRULY BELIEVE IN THE MISSION OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND THE
WAY THEY HELP PEOPLE EVERY DAY AND JUST BEING PART OF THAT
MADE ME FEEL THAT IT WAS CERTAINLY BIGGER THAN MYSELF
AND I DID THAT FOR 24 YEARS AND IT WAS SAD TO LEAVE BUT I
THINK IS THE RIGHT TIME FOR ME AND I'M VERY HAPPY HOW THINGS
ARE NOW AT THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND THE PEOPLE THAT ARE THERE
AND I LOOK FORWARD TO SEEING ALL NEW SYSTEMS THAT ARE BEING
CREATED THAT AFTER I LEAVE BUT AGAIN THANK YOU.
>> IT WAS TRULY AN HONOR TO DISTRICT FOUR SUPERVISOR WANG
THANK YOU PRESIDENT MENDELSOHN AND COLLEAGUES, I'M PROUD TO
RECOGNIZE THE AMERICAN HEART ASSOCIATION.
>> I WAIT FOR THEM TO COME UP DURING THE AMERICAN HEART MONTH
FOR THE INCREDIBLE WORK THEY DO TO SAVE LIVES CARDIAC ARREST IS
ONE OF THE LEADING CAUSES OF DEATH EVERY YEAR MORE THAN
350,000 CARDIAC ARRESTS HAPPEN OUTSIDE HOSPITALS IN THE UNITED
STATES. MOST ARE FATAL.
WHAT'S STRIKING IS THAT 70% HAPPEN AT HOME SO THE PERSON
STANDING NEXT TO YOU OFTEN LOVED ONE CAN MAKE ALL THE
DIFFERENCE. IMMEDIATE CPR CAN DOUBLE OR
EVEN TRIPLE SURVIVAL. YET ONLY 41% OF PEOPLE GET CPR
FROM SOMEONE NEARBY. THE AMERICAN HEART
ASSOCIATION'S NATION OF LIFESAVERS INITIATIVE AIMS TO
CHANGE THAT BY EMPOWERING EVERYONE TO LEARN CPR AND USE
AID'S DOUBLING SURVIVAL FROM OUT OF HOSPITAL CARDIAC ARREST
BY 2030. AND THAT MISSION REALLY
RESONATES WITH ME DURING MY SERVICE AS AN AMERICORPS MEMBER
IN THE ARMY NATIONAL GUARD. AND WHILE WORKING ON THE
CHALLENGE COUNCIL I CONSISTENT LEE PROMOTED THE WORK OF
NONPROFITS AND CPR AND 80 TRAININGS AND I SAW FIRSTHAND
HOW THESE SKILLS SAVED LIVES AND IN ONE INSTANCE
IN PARTICULAR WHEN I USED TO WORK AT AT PIER 39 FOR FOR
SECURITY WE RESPONDED TO TO CPR AND SOMEBODY WAS HAVING A HEART
ATTACK IN ONE OF THE RESTAURANTS AND MY FELLOW
SECURITY OFFICERS AND I WE WERE TRAINED IN CPR AND ONE OF THEM
TOOK TOOK THE LEAD IN GIVING MOUTH TO MOUTH AND CPR AND WE
WERE ABLE TO SUPPORT THAT PERSON UNTIL EMERGENCY
AND PARAMEDICS ARRIVED IN DISTRICT FOUR, THE AMERICAN
HEART ASSOCIATION WORKED WITH OCEAN PARK HEALTH CENTER,
SUNSET HEALTH SERVICES AND SELF-HELP FOR THE ELDERLY
TO SUPPORT PATIENTS AND SENIORS IN CONTROLLING THE HIGH BLOOD
PRESSURE. THEY BROUGHT HANDS ONLY CPR
DEMONSTRATIONS TURNED COMMUNITY HEALTH FAIRS WITH OUTREACH
IN CHINESE AND TAGALOG TO REACH A NHP ASIAN AMERICAN NATIVE
HAWAIIAN PACIFIC ISLANDER COMMUNITIES ESPECIALLY WOMEN
WHO ARE LESS LIKELY TO RECEIVE CPR IN EMERGENCIES CITYWIDE.
>> THEIR OUTREACH CAMPAIGNS HAVE REACHED 75,000 SAN
FRANCISCANS AND THROUGH PARTNERSHIPS OF HOSPITALS,
CLINICS AND CONSULATES AND CAN BE BASED ORGANIZATIONS, THEY'VE
HELPED THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS LEARN CPR, IMPROVE NUTRITION
AND ACCESS QUALITY CARE FOR HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE.
THIS WORK MATTERS AND MAKES OUR CITY STRONGER AND IT REMINDS US
THAT ANY ONE OF US CAN BE A LIFESAVER.
ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, THANK YOU TO THE
AMERICAN HEART ASSOCIATION FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND COMMITMENT
TO BUILDING A NATION OF LIFESAVERS RIGHT HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO AND IN OUR SUNSET COMMUNITY.
I LIKE TO RECOGNIZE THEIR LEADERSHIP TEAM.
JOINING US TODAY DR. JOHN MEYER LIVES IN MUD.
LIZZIE FELTON AND SARAH FINE THANK YOU.
WITH THAT I WOULD LIKE TO TURN IT OVER TO LIZA MUDD, REGIONAL
SENIOR VICE PRESIDENT OF THE AMERICAN HEART ASSOCIATION.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, SUPERVISOR WANG WE REALLY
APPRECIATE BEING HERE AND THANK YOU FOR THE CITY FOR
RECOGNIZING FEBRUARY AS AMERICAN HEART MONTH.
>> FOR MORE THAN A CENTURY THE HEART ASSOCIATION HAS BEEN
WORKING TO SAVE AND IMPROVE LIVES AND WE APPRECIATE YOUR
SUPPORT OF THE MISSION HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
>> LIKE SUPERVISOR WANG SAID, THE HEART ASSOCIATION HAS LONG
CHAMPIONED CPR AND SPECIFICALLY HANDS ONLY CPR THROUGH OUR
NATION OF LIFESAVERS CAMPAIGN. >> THIS YEAR WE'RE SPREADING
THE MESSAGE THAT YOU ARE THE FIRST RESPONDER UNTIL HELP
ARRIVES SO THAT EVERY ONE OF US IS PREPARED TO REACT IN A
CARDIAC EMERGENCY. >> THE STEPS ARE SIMPLE.
>> FIRST CALL 911 TO LOCATE AN AID.
AND THREE KNOW HOW TO PERFORM CPR.
>> WE'VE BEEN PROUD TO SERVE COMMUNITIES THROUGHOUT SAN
FRANCISCO IN THE MANY WAYS SUPER SUPERVISOR WANG MENTIONED
AND ESPECIALLY IN DISTRICT FOUR TO PROMOTE THE WELL-BEING OF
ITS RESIDENTS SO THAT EVERYONE CAN LIVE LONGER AND HEALTHIER
LIVES. >> THIS FRIDAY WE'LL BE
CELEBRATING MORE THAN 20 YEARS OF COMMITMENT TO CHAMPION
CHAMPIONING WOMEN'S HEALTH AT OUR ANNUAL GO RED FOR WOMEN
LUNCHEON IN SAN FRANCISCO. AND THIS FALL SAN FRANCISCO CAN
HELP EXPAND OUR NATION OF LIFESAVERS MOVEMENT AND BRING
AWARENESS TO HEART HEALTH AND WELL-BEING IN PART BY
PARTICIPATING IN THE BAY AREA HEART WALK A COMMUNITY EVENT
IN CHINA BASIN PARK ON SEPTEMBER 24TH.
>> THE HEART ON BEHALF OF THE HEART ASSOCIATION WE GRATEFULLY
ACCEPT THIS COMMENDATION AND THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO CONTINUED SUPPORT OF OUR WORK.
>> THANK YOU. TO
AND FROM DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> COLLEAGUES THIS BLACK HISTORY MONTH IT IS MY HONOR TO
RECOGNIZE PHYLLIS BOWIE PROUD FILLMORE NATIVE AND FOOD
JUSTICE ADVOCATE WHO IS MAKING BLACK HISTORY MONTH EVERY DAY
BY SHAPING HOW OUR CITY UNDERSTANDS FOOD ACCESS
AND COMMUNITY HEALTH AND UPLIFTING THE IMPORTANCE OF
FOOD JUSTICE IN THE WESTERN TRADITION.
FIRST COMING UP PHYLLIS WAS RAISED IN THE FILLMORE IN THE
1960S BY HER MOTHER, A MEMBER OF THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY.
MISS BOWIE'S ACTIVISM BEGAN EARLY.
AS A CHILD SHE MARCHED FOR CIVIL RIGHTS AT CITY HALL
AND FOR HER ADVOCACY HAS ALWAYS BEEN LIVED AND PRACTICED.
>> PHYLLIS BUILT A SUCCESSFUL CAREER AS AN INTERIOR DESIGNER
AND APPEARED ON NETWORKS INCLUDING HGTV, ABC AND TV1.
>> SHE LATER FOUNDED AND HOSTED THE AWARD WINNING LIVING WITH
PHYLLIS URBAN FOOD SHOW FOCUSED ON EDUCATING FAMILIES ABOUT
FOOD INSECURITY. URBAN AGRICULTURE AND FOOD
SOVEREIGNTY. THROUGH HER POPULAR FOOD
EDUCATION SEGMENTS, SHE SHOWED VIEWERS HOW TO PREPARE HEALTHY
RESTAURANT QUALITY MEALS USING ACCESSIBLE INGREDIENTS WHILE
ELEVATING CULTURALLY RELEVANT FOOD TRADITIONS
AND INTERVIEWING LOCAL CHEFS. >> FOR MORE THAN TWO DECADES,
PHYLLIS HAS ADVANCED HOUSING AND FOOD JUSTICE IN DISTRICT
FIVE. SHE'S SUPPORTED MIDTOWN PARK
RESIDENTS BY PROTECTING THEM FROM DISPLACEMENT AND DURING
THE PANDEMIC TRULY STEPPED UP FOR HER COMMUNITY.
SHE PERSONALLY CARRIED HEAVY BAGS OF GROCERIES UP MULTIPLE
FLIGHTS OF STAIRS TO ENSURE SENIORS AND FAMILIES RECEIVED
FOOD SAFELY AT THEIR DOORS. >> ONE RESIDENT SHARED WITH US
THAT HER GOAL WAS TO MAKE SURE NO ONE WAS LEFT WITHOUT SUPPORT
DURING SUCH A DIFFICULT TIME. SHE VOLUNTEERS OFTEN DAILY WITH
ORGANIZATIONS INCLUDING GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH, THE SALVATION
ARMY, THE SAN FRANCISCO MARIN FOODBANK PROJECT OPEN HAND
AND BOOKER T WASHINGTON COMMUNITY SERVICE CENTER
DELIVERING FOOD TO SENIORS LOW INCOME RESIDENTS, INDIVIDUALS
LIVING WITH HIV AND MEDICALLY VULNERABLE NEIGHBORS THROUGHOUT
THE FILLMORE AND THE BAY AREA. RESIDENTS DESCRIBE HER HOW HOW
HER DAILY ONE ON ONE CHECK INS MADE THE DAY FOR THOSE SHE
SERVED. >> HER LEADERSHIP EXTENDS TO
YOUTH EMPOWERMENT AND EDUCATION AS WELL.
SHE CREATED THE BLACK FOOD SOVEREIGNTY PROGRAM PROVIDING
SUMMER INTERNSHIPS FOR STUDENTS AT GATEWAY HIGH SCHOOL.
THESE STUDENTS BUILT VEGETABLE GARDENS IN THE FILLMORE PUBLIC
HOUSING LEARNED ABOUT NUTRITION AND THE DANGERS OF PROCESSED
FOOD AND PREPARED FRESH MEALS FOR SENIORS AT BOOKER T
WASHINGTON. >> I PERSONALLY HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO VISIT THE GARDEN WITH MS..
MS.. >> BOWIE HERSELF WALKING
ALONGSIDE HER HEARING DIRECTLY FROM THE STUDENTS AND SEEING
THE CARE AND PRIDE THEY PUT INTO EVERY RAISED BED.
MADE IT CLEAR TO ME THAT THIS IS SO MUCH MORE THAN A PROGRAM
ON PAPER. >> DR. ALICIA MONTGOMERY,
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE GATEWAY PUBLIC SCHOOL, SAID
BEST MS. PHILLIS EMBODIES EVERYTHING SHE STANDS FOR
JUSTICE, HEALTH, WELL-BEING AND ACCESS.
GATEWAY IS PROUD TO HAVE HER AS A PARTNER.
>> MOST RECENTLY MS. BOWIE PRESENTED PRESENTED BEFORE THE
SAN FRANCISCO SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT OVERSIGHT BOARD TO
ADVOCATE FOR IMPROVED ACCESS TO NUTRITIOUS HEALTH SUPPORTING
MEALS WITHIN OUR JAIL SYSTEM. >> IN A LETTER TO MY OFFICE
SUPPORTING TODAY'S RECOGNITION ,THE BOARD EXPRESSED GRATITUDE
FOR HER WILLINGNESS TO ENGAGE WITH OVERSIGHT BODIES
AND CONTRIBUTE HER KNOWLEDGE, ADVOCACY AND LIVE PERSPECTIVE,
NOTING THAT HER WORK ADVANCES THE SHARED GOAL OF ENSURING
THAT OUR SYSTEMS REFLECT HEALTH FAIRNESS AND RESPECT FOR ALL
RESIDENTS. AND ALSO NOTE THAT WHILE
PREPARING THIS COMMENDATION, OUR OFFICE RECEIVED SO MANY
UNPROMPTED EMAILS FROM NUMEROUS COMMUNITY MEMBERS ALL OF WHICH
CELEBRATED HER COMPASSION, TIMELESSNESS AND DEEP
COMMITMENT TO THOSE SHE SERVES. THAT IS JUST HOW BELOVED SHE
IS. ONE RESIDENT PROBABLY DESCRIBED
HER AS SAN FRANCISCO'S NUMBER ONE VOLUNTEER AND EDUCATOR ON
FOOD SECURITY. ANOTHER WROTE HER DEDICATION
AND HARD WORK ARE TRULY INVALUABLE TO THE FILLMORE.
THROUGH HER WORKS IN MEDIA MENTORSHIP DIRECT SERVICE
AND POLICY ADVOCACY, PHYLLIS HAS ENSURED THAT FOOD SECURITY
IN THE FILLMORE IS ALWAYS AT THE FOREFRONT.
PHYLLIS ON BEHALF OF DISTRICT FIVE IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF
SAN FRANCISCO, WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND YOUR
UNWAVERING DEDICATION TO ENSURING THAT EVERY RESIDENT
DESERVES ACCESS TO NOURISHMENT AND DIGNITY.
>> THE FLOOR IS YOURS. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
MY SUPERVISOR. I FIRST WANT TO THANK GOD
ALMIGHTY FOR MY STRENGTH FOR TELLING ME TO GO FORWARD
BECAUSE I THINK IT'S ONE OF THE SADDEST THINGS THAT IN ONE OF
THE RICHEST COUNTRIES AND ONE OF THE RICHEST CITIES THAT WE
HAVE CHILDREN AND WE HAVE SENIORS GOING TO BED HUNGRY.
>> BASICS Y'ALL. I HAVE A BLACK COMMUNITY
IN MIDTOWN PARK APARTMENTS THAT HAS BEEN PROMISED OWNERSHIP
AND WE STILL DON'T HAVE IT. WE'RE TALKING BASICS LIKE
SHELTER AND FOOD. I WANT TO SECONDLY THANK MY
MOTHER MRS. JEANNIE BUI WHO SHE PUT SO MUCH INTO MY BROTHER
AND I WITH THE HIGHEST EDUCATION THAT MONEY COULD BUY
AND HER COMMITMENT TO ME WAS YOU TAKE THIS AND YOU FURTHER
OUR COMMUNITY WHATEVER AREA YOU FIND.
THE BLACK PANTHERS WAS ABOUT FOOD AND BREAKFAST FOR CHILDREN
AND I'M FOLLOWING THAT. >> I WANT TO SAY THANK YOU TO I
FEEL THE ENERGY OF MY FRIENDS AND FAMILY BEHIND ME.
THOSE WHO COULDN'T COME. THOSE WHO WROTE IN.
THIS IS A TOUGH JOB TO BE A COMMUNITY LEADER AND TO FIGHT
FOR JUSTICE. IN THE FILM WORLD WHERE WE HAVE
LIQUOR STORES ON EVERY CORNER AND WE HAVE EVERY FAST FOOD
RESTAURANT WITHIN JUST A FOUR BLOCK AREA, I WANT TO THANK
EVERYBODY THAT'S IN THE ROOM TODAY THAT KNOWS MY STORY, THAT
KNOWS MY FIGHT AND THAT KNOWS THAT I WILL NEVER I WILL NEVER
STOP FIGHTING. IT'S HARD TO DO THIS BUT I WAS
MEANT TO DO IT. IT'S IN MY GUT.
SOME OF US HAVE IT. LIKE ALL OF THESE WONDERFUL
PEOPLE THAT JUST GOT THE SAME TYPE OF AWARDS IT'S IN YOUR
GUT. IT'S SOMETHING THAT YOU JUST
CAN'T STOP AND TRUST ME. EVERYBODY WHO'S IN HERE WHO
KNOWS ME I'VE QUIT SEVERAL TIMES BECAUSE MY FEELINGS GET
HURT REALLY EASILY. >> I WANT TO NOW ALSO THANK THE
SUPERVISORS. I WANT TO THANK THE CITY
AND THE COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND ONE ESPECIALLY THINK MY
SUPERVISOR FOR STARTING THE REDESIGN OF FILLMORE.
IS IT GOING TO HAPPEN IN MY LIFETIME?
I HOPE SO. BUT I ALSO KNOW IT TAKES SMALL
STEPS AND IT TAKES COMMITMENT, CONSISTENCY TO FIND WHAT'S
RIGHT. I JUST KNOW AT THE END OF THIS
WE'RE GOING TO WIN AND OUR CHILDREN THOSE WONDERFUL
CHILDREN AT GATEWAY I ALSO WORK WITH CHILDREN AT THE UNIVERSITY
OF SAN FRANCISCO AND COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT AND THAT'S OUR
FUTURE. >> FOR ME TO TEACH THEM HOW TO
TAKE A SEAT AND GROW AND HARVEST COLLARD GREENS
AND THEN THEY GO HOME AND TELL THEIR PARENTS HOW TO EAT
HEALTHILY. >> I WANT TO ALSO THANK.
>> EXCUSE ME. I WANT TO THINK A COUPLE OF
ORGANIZATIONS BOOKER T WASHINGTON BEING THE NUMBER ONE
THAT IN 2020 AFTER GEORGE FLOYD I HAD A NERVOUS BREAKDOWN
AND THEY LITERALLY EMBRACED ME AND HEALS ME WITH ALL THE
WONDERFUL SERVICES THAT THEY PROVIDE TO THE FILLMORE AND TO
PEOPLE WHO LOOK LIKE ME. I WANT TO SAY THANK YOU.
I WILL CONTINUE THIS AND I WELCOME ALL THE OTHER
SUPERVISORS TO COME INTO KNOWING THAT THE FILLMORE NEEDS
HELP RIGHT NOW. >> WHY DO WE HAVE LIQUOR STORES
IN EVERY CORNER? I DON'T SEE THAT IN ANY OTHER
NEIGHBORHOOD. WHY IS IT OTHER NEIGHBORHOOD
KIDS HAVE FRESH FRUITS AND VEGETABLES?
THAT'S ETHNIC TO LEAF FOR THEM? WHY DOESN'T THE FILLMORE HAVE
THAT? WHY DO WE HAVE FAST FOODS THAT
POISON US? WHY DO WE HAVE KIDNEY DIALYSIS
CENTERS OPEN UP MORE THAN WE DO FRESH GROCERY STORES.
THESE ARE RHETORICAL QUESTIONS AND THESE ARE QUESTIONS I
REALLY WANTED TO BE ON THE FOREFRONT OF ALL OF YOU.
YOU HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY. THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS
UNEXPECTED RECOGNITION. ONE OF THE THINGS I LEARNED
PROBABLY AFTER MY FIRST TEN YEARS WORKING AT MIDTOWN IS I
AM ACCOUNTABLE TO ME. I GIVE ME THE AWARDS BECAUSE I
KNOW WHAT I DO WHEN IT'S DARK AND WHEN I'M SAD AND HUNGRY.
>> I WANT TO THINK MYSELF FOR STAYING TO IT AND LOOKING
FABULOUS WHEN I DO. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR ALL MY PATIENCE AND SAY THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. >> I LOVE YOU MORE
. >> DISTRICT SIX SUPERVISOR
DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN.
>> KAITLYN SO COLLEAGUES, AS WE CELEBRATE AS WE CELEBRATE BLACK
HISTORY MONTH, I WANTED TO HONOR SOMEONE WHO REPRESENTS A
STANDOUT LOCAL EXAMPLE OF THE LONG AND HISTORICALLY
CONSEQUENTIAL INTERSECTIONALITY OF THE BLACK COMMUNITY WITH THE
MOVEMENT FOR LGBTQ EQUALITY. THIS IS A HISTORY REPRESENTED
BY SUCH LEGENDS AS STONEWALL'S MARSHA P JOHNSON THE CIVIL
RIGHTS MOVEMENT BAYARD RUSTIN AND WARRIOR POET AUDRE LORDE
IN MY VIEW KAITLYN ELISE FOWLER IS EVERY BIT THE WORTHY LOCAL
SUCCESSOR TO THAT HISTORY FOR HER FEARLESSNESS, HER TIRELESS
WORK ETHIC AND HER LEADERSHIP IN DELIVERING REAL CHANGE
AND FOR BEING AN INSPIRATION TO COUNTLESS SAN FRANCISCANS.
KAYLEEN IS SOMEONE WHO DOESN'T WAIT FOR SYSTEMS TO CHANGE.
SHE BUILDS WHAT'S MISSING AND IN OUR CITY THAT HAS MEANT
CREATING NEW WAYS TO CONNECT PEOPLE TO CARE TO COMMUNITY
AND TO OPPORTUNITY ESPECIALLY FOR TRANS WOMEN WHO HAVE BEEN
SO OFTEN OVERLOOKED AND WHO ARE TODAY FACING LEVELS OF
DEHUMANIZATION AND INVECTIVE IN NATIONAL POLITICS UNLIKE
ANYTHING WE'VE EVER SEEN BEFORE.
YET THAT IS EXACTLY WHY KYLIN STRENGTH AND STEADY HANDED
LEADERSHIP MATTERS SO MUCH. >> AT THE SAN FRANCISCO
COMMUNITY HEALTH CENTER SHE SAW A GAP IN HOW PEOPLE WERE BEING
REACHED AND SUPPORTED. AS A CASE MANAGER SHE DEVELOPED
AN ENGAGEMENT MODEL DESIGNED TO CONNECT TRANS WOMEN TO
COMPREHENSIVE AFFIRMING CARE. IT WAS THOUGHTFUL.
IT WAS COMMUNITY DRIVEN AND IT WORKED.
THAT MODEL WENT ON TO RECEIVE NATIONAL RECOGNITION FROM THE
CENTERS FOR DISEASE CONTROL AND PREVENTION.
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY IT HELPED PEOPLE ACCESS CARE IN A WAY
THAT FELT RESPECTFUL AND ACCESSIBLE.
BUILDING ON THAT WORK KYLIN HELPED TO BRING TO LIFE THE SHE
BOUTIQUE ONE OF THE MOST CREATIVE, JOYFUL
AND CELEBRATORY SERVICE PROGRAMS I HAVE SEEN IN OUR
CITY. THE SHE BOUTIQUE IS A WELCOMING
SHOPPING EXPERIENCE CREATED BY TRANS WOMEN FOR TRANS WOMEN.
IT'S A PLACE WHERE WOMEN CAN ACCESS BRAND NEW CLOTHING
AND ACCESSORIES, PICK OUT ITEMS THAT HELP EXPRESS WHO THEY ARE.
ENJOY A MOCKTAIL AND SPEND TIME IN A WELCOMING AND AFFIRMING
ENVIRONMENT. IT'S ABOUT MORE THAN CLOTHING.
IT'S ABOUT DIGNITY AND CONFIDENCE AND COMMUNITY.
A WHILE BACK I HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO VISIT THE SHE
BOUTIQUE AT THE NEW TRANS THRIVES FACILITY AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO COMMUNITY HEALTH CENTER.
AND WHAT STOOD OUT TO ME WAS HOW INTENTIONAL IT IS.
IT'S NOT JUST A SERVICE BUT A SPECIAL AND UNIQUE SPACE THAT
BRINGS PEOPLE TOGETHER, BUILD TRUST IN COMMUNITY AND MAKES
PEOPLE FEEL NOT JUST SEEN BUT CELEBRATED.
AND THAT REFLECTS KAITLYNN HERSELF.
WHEN YOU MEET HER YOU'RE IMMEDIATELY CAPTIVATED BY HER
CONTAGIOUS POSITIVE ENERGY. SHE BRINGS PEOPLE TOGETHER, SHE
BUILDS CONNECTION AND SHE LEADS THE WAY IN A WAY THAT IS BOTH
GROUNDED AND UPLIFTING. KAITLYN'S LEADERSHIP ALSO
EXTENDS FAR BEYOND A SINGLE PROGRAM OR A SINGLE CITY.
SHE MADE HISTORY AS THE FIRST TRANS WOMAN TO SERVE AS A
COMMISSIONER ON THE ALAMEDA COUNTY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS
OF WOMEN WHERE SHE CHAMPIONED POLICIES FOCUSED ON SAFETY,
ECONOMIC EMPOWERMENT AND HEALTH CARE EQUITY.
>> SHE SERVES AS THE EXECUTIVE BOARD MEMBER OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO LGBT COMMUNITY CENTER AND AS A VICE CHAIR OF THE
BAYARD RUSTIN LGBTQ PLUS VICTORY FUND LEADERSHIP COUNCIL
HELPING TO SUPPORT LGBTQ PLUS LEADERS RUNNING FOR OFFICE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY. AND SHE'S AN ACTIVE MEMBER OF
THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA LGBTQ PLUS CAUCUS AND IN ONE OF HER
MOST IMPACTFUL EFFORTS SHE FOUNDED THE FIRST SORORITY
DEDICATED SPECIFICALLY TO YOUNG TRANS WOMEN FOCUSED ON STI
AND HIV PREVENTION. LEADERSHIP DEVELOPMENT
AND SISTERHOOD AT A TIME WHEN THIS KIND OF WORK IS FACING
UNPRECEDENTED CHALLENGES, SHE CONTINUES TO LEAD WITH COURAGE,
WITH CLASS AND WITH A CLEAR SENSE OF PURPOSE.
COLLEAGUES, KAITLYN'S WORK HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO IS HELPING TO
SHAPE HOW WE THINK ABOUT CARE, HOW WE BUILD COMMUNITY AND HOW
WE SHOW UP FOR ONE ANOTHER. SHE IS NOT JUST IMPROVING
INDIVIDUAL LIVES. SHE IS HELPING TO SET A HIGHER
STANDARD FOR HOW OUR CITY SERVES ITS PEOPLE.
IT IS MY PRIVILEGE TO RECOGNIZE HER TODAY AND TO HONOR HER FOR
EVERYTHING SHE HAS CONTRIBUTED TO SAN FRANCISCO.
KAITLYN, THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP, YOUR VISION AND FOR
THE DIFFERENCE YOU CONTINUE TO MAKE FOR OUR COMMUNITY AND OUR
CITY. >> CONGRATULATIONS TO YOU.
THE FLOOR IS YOURS AND BEFORE BEFORE YOU SPEAK I JUST WANT TO
THANK SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR DOING THIS COMMENDATION.
I AM ALSO IN THE KAITLYN FAN CLUB AND YOU DO JUST HAVE THE
WARM MOST MOST CHARMING LOVELY WAY.
YOU ARE SO SWEET AND YOU ARE SO EXCELLENT ON A PANEL AS WELL
AND YOU HAVE DONE SUCH GREAT WORK IN SAN FRANCISCO AND IN
THE EAST BAY AND ALL OF US WHO'VE GOTTEN TO MEET YOU WORK
WITH YOU BE IN YOUR PRESENCE FOR A MINUTE ARE LUCKY SO THANK
YOU AGAIN SUPERVISOR DORSEY AND CONGRATULATIONS KAITLYN
FOWLER. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH TO ALL THE
SUPERVISORS ESPECIALLY SUPERVISOR DORSEY STANDING
BEFORE YOU TODAY. I'M HUMBLED AND GRATEFUL FOR
THIS MOMENT OF RECOGNITION UNDERSTANDING THIS ASSIGNMENT
IT'S OFTEN THE EASY PART BUT IT'S IN THE PREPARATION OF
CREATING A LESSON PLAN WHERE REAL CHALLENGES BEGIN AND IT IS
HERE THAT DETAIL THE DETAILS OF STRATEGIZING AND PLANNING THAT
WE DISCOVER THE NEED OF OUR COMMUNITY, OUR ROLES AS LEADERS
TO FIND A SOLUTION THAT RESONATES WITH EVERYONE
AND MAKING IT ESSENTIAL TO BE MAKING IT ESSENTIAL TO BE
INTENTIONAL. WE MUST KNOW HOW TO MEET PEOPLE
WHERE THEY ARE ESPECIALLY FACING CHALLENGING SITUATIONS
AS A TRANSWOMAN PARTICULARLY AN AFRICAN-AMERICAN TRANS WOMAN I
AM ACUTELY AWARE OF THAT WE HAVE BECOME A TARGET IN THIS
POLITICAL CLIMATE. YET I HAVE ALWAYS BELIEVED
IN TRUE LEADERSHIP JUST DOESN'T OFFER SOLUTIONS BUT WE CREATE
THEM. IF I COULD FIND IF I CAN'T FIND
A SOLUTION I RELY ON MY COMMUNITY OFFERING THEM A SEAT
AT THE TABLE SO THAT WE COULD COME TOGETHER AND IDENTIFY WHAT
TRULY WORKS FOR US. >> I STAND HERE TODAY BECAUSE I
NEVER GAVE UP. IN A CLIMATE WHERE OUR VOICES
ARE OFTEN OVERLOOK OR DISREGARDED, RESILIENCE IS
ESSENTIAL TO ME AND THIS JOURNEY.
THERE ARE SOME INDIVIDUALS THAT I MUST ACKNOWLEDGED.
FIRST I WANT TO THANK MYSELF FOR NOT GIVING UP.
EACH OF US HAVE A STORY THAT SHAPE WHO WE ARE.
AND FOR ME THE JOURNEY HAS BEGAN ALWAYS WITH PERSEVERANCE
AND COMMITMENT. I WANT TO EXPRESS MY GRATITUDE
TO SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR RECOGNIZING MY EFFORTS
IN FOSTERING A MORE AWARE AND MORE HEALTHIER COMMUNITY.
YOUR SUPPORT IS TRULY LOVING AND UNFORGIVING.
UNFORGETTABLE. >> I'M SORRY.
I WOULD LIKE TO EXPRESS A BIG THANK YOU TO ONE OF THE BEST
CEOS AND EXECUTIVE DIRECTORS IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO, LANCE TOMA FOR TRUSTING MY VISION AND GRANTING
ME THE PLATFORM TO LEAD YOUR BELIEVE IN ME HAVE ALLOWED ME
TO CONNECT IN SO MANY LEVELS IN THIS SIGNIFICANT JOURNEY.
>> A MASSIVE THANK YOU GOES OUT TO THE ENTIRE STAFF OF SAN
FRANCISCO COMMUNITY HEALTH CENTER FOR ALLOWING ME TO LEAD
AND FOR GIVING ME THEIR UNWAVERING SUPPORT.
TOGETHER WE MAKE STRIDES TOWARDS A MORE INCLUSIVE FUTURE
AND TO MY SISTER SOKO THANK YOU FOR KEEPING ME GROUNDED CARING
AND RE-ENERGIZING ME WHEN I FEEL LOW YOUR LOVE AND SUPPORT
AND YOUR BACKBONE OF MY STRENGTH.
AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST I WANT TO THANK MY PARENTS FOR
RECOGNIZING AS A LEADER IN ME AT AN EARLY AGE.
THEY'VE EQUIPPED ME WITH THE ESSENTIAL TOOLS THAT I NEED TO
NAVIGATE IN TODAY'S SOCIETY. THEY TAUGHT ME THAT IF I'M NOT
INVITED TO THE TABLE, BUILD ONE AS I CONCLUDE I LEAVE YOU WITH
THIS THOUGHT. IF YOU FIND YOURSELF IN THE
POSITION OF LEADERSHIP, DON'T TAKE IT LIGHTLY.
PEOPLE VOTED AND PEOPLE HAVE POINTED US FOR A REASON.
THEY TRUST OUR VISION THIS PLACE THAT THEIR TRUST OUR
VISION IS FOR REASON. THEY SEE OUR POTENTIAL AND IT
IS UP TO US TO CARRY THE LOAD AND REMAIN INTENTIONAL
AND NEVER EVER RISE ABOVE THE COMMUNITIES THAT WE SERVE.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS RECOGNITION
. >> DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN
THANK YOU FOR YOUR PRESENCE. >> OH, SORRY.
CAN YOU GO UP TO THE PODIUM? COLLEAGUES, I AM PROUD TO HONOR
JOANNE XIONG, FOUNDER OF THE AMERICAN ART INSTITUTE.
>> LOCATE IN. >> LOCATED IN DISTRICT 11 I
OFFERS PROGRAMING FOR YOUNG STUDENTS AND ADULTS DRAWING,
PAINTING, DANCE AND OTHER VISUAL ART CLASSES.
>> OVER THE LAST 20 YEARS JOHANNA HAS BEEN DEVOTED TO
PROMOTING CHINESE TRADITIONAL CULTURE THROUGH ART, DANCE
AND MOTION PICTURES. SHE FOUND THE SAN FRANCISCO
INTERNATIONAL A NEW CONCEPT FILM FESTIVAL TO PROMOTE
INDEPENDENT FILM MAKERS. >> JOANNA HERSELF HAS ALSO
DIRECTED, WROTE AND PRODUCED MANY SHORT FILMS.
SHE HAS WON AWARDS FOR ACTING, DIRECTING AND PRODUCING
IN SEVERAL FILM FESTIVALS. >> FOR HER FOR THE CHAMPION OF
FLETCHER'S PHILANTHROPIC EFFORTS, JOANNA WAS AWARDED THE
2023 U.S. PRESIDENT ARTS VOLUNTEER SERVICES AWARD FOR
HER ACTING ENGAGEMENT IN COMMUNITY NONPROFITS.
>> JOANNA HAS ALSO SERVED AS THE PRESIDENT OF THE CHINESE
CONSOLIDATED WOMEN'S ASSOCIATIONS.
>> HER ARTISTRY AND INVOLVEMENT IN ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY IS AN
INSPIRATION FOR FUTURE GENERATIONS.
THANK YOU JOANNA FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP COMMITMENT TO
MAINTAINING OUR CULTURE AND FOSTERING THE ARTS FOR OUR
YOUTH ESPECIALLY IN DISTRICT 11 AND SAN FRANCISCO.
AND I ALSO WOULD LIKE TO SAY A FEW WHERE IN CHINESE JANE ALEJO
COMING OFF SEASON DOING HUNG HIGH EATING BEAUTIFULLY JOCELYN
LEE ZHANG IN ZHANG YING I LIKE YOUR LAND SELECTED ON MOUNTAINS
ARE CHOOSING TO MANGA YOU SHOULD CHECK OUT YOUR WANG
LOGIC ESSAY COPY YOUR DEMO SO AGAIN THE INTENTION AND TYPE
YOU DON'T LIKE THAT YOU'RE CALLING THOUGH KANGAROO DOG
ACCORDING TO MY CIRCLE LONGO TOGA AISHA COMES OUT DON'T MIND
IF I GET TO MY MAYO LEGAL NIGGLING DON'T YOU MEAN YOUR
HAYATI HER YOUNGER ENJOYMENT COMES ANYWAY SOME FANCY COYOTE
DILATE SOME SEEDS OR GET YOU HOW DOES ALLIE THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR SUPERVISOR CHARLENE CHEN THANK YOU FOR ALL THE CDC
ADVISORS OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR YOUR HARD WORK I'M JOINED AS A
FOUNDER AND THE PRESIDENT OF AMERICAN ART INSTITUTE AND THE
SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL. >> YOUR CONCEPT THE FILM
FESTIVAL OUR AMERICA ART INSTITUTE FOUNDED IN 2009.
>> WE ARE A MATURE THE SCHOOL WE OFFER FINE ART, MUSIC, DANCE
THE DRAMA CLASSES FOR BOTH CHILDREN AND ADULTS FOR MANY
YEARS WE OFFER AND OFFER SERVICES FOR UNDERSERVED
COMMUNITIES AS WE ALWAYS HAVE A CHARITY VOLUNTEERING
PERFORMANCE FOR SENIORS AND THE SHOJI I'M PROUD OF OUR
DISTRICT. THE 11 NOW IS A BETTER AND THE
BETTER SO WE WILL CONTINUE TO PROMULGATE PROMOTE THE CHINESE
TRADITIONAL CULTURE AND THE ALSO WE DEVELOPING A FRIENDSHIP
BETWEEN AMERICAN PEOPLE AND THE CHINESE PEOPLE.
HERE COMES OUR SCHOOLMATES, OUR DANCERS FROM OUR SCHOOL.
>> COME ON. >> OKAY.
WE COME HERE TO CELEBRATE THEM. >> THANKS AGAIN.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR YOUR SENTENCE SUPERVISORS THE
RECOGNITION AND THE CONFIRMATION.
>> THANK YOU
. ALL RIGHT.
AND FINALLY RAYMOND CLARK, COME ON UP.
LOOKS LIKE YOU HAVE KIDS WITH YOU.
>> MAYBE BRING THE KIDS IF YOU LIKE.
MAYBE. >> POSSIBLY THEY'RE BEING
CAJOLED. THEY'RE SAYING NO, NO, DAD, NO,
WE'RE NOT INTO IT. OKAY?
NOT TODAY. NOT TODAY.
MAYBE NEXT DAY. >> OKAY, COLLEAGUES, IT IS MY
GREAT HONOR TO PRESENT A SPECIAL COMMENDATION TODAY TO
RAYMOND CLARK, PRESIDENT OF THE GLEN PARK MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION
AND OWNER OF THE CLARK TECHNIQUE.
THE GPM IS A SMALL BUT MIGHTY ORGANIZATION.
I. I SEE SOME OF ITS LEADERS OUT
IN THE AUDIENCE. IT REMINDS ME OF THAT MARGARET
MEAD QUOTE ABOUT A SMALL NUMBER OF CITIZENS BEING ABLE TO
CHANGE THE WORLD. AND FOR THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS
THAT ORGANIZATION AND THE ENTIRE NEIGHBORHOOD HAVE
BENEFITED FROM RAYMOND'S EFFORTS AND FOR THE LAST YEAR
FROM HIS LEADERSHIP AS THE ORGANIZATION'S HEAD DURING THAT
TIME HE'S BECOME A TRUE NEIGHBORHOOD CHAMPION
ORGANIZING COMMUNITY EVENTS, LOBBYING FOR IMPROVEMENT FUNDS
AND ELEVATING NEIGHBORHOOD CONCERNS ACROSS A RANGE OF
ISSUES INCLUDING PLANNING, ZONING, TRANSPORTATION AND THE
ENVIRONMENT. DURING RAYMOND'S TENURE, GLEN
PARK HAS FLOURISHED EVEN GAINING WORLD WIDE RECOGNITION
AFTER BEING RANKED ONE OF THE COOLEST NEIGHBORHOODS IN THE
WORLD BY TIME OUT LAST YEAR. >> CONGRATULATIONS, PRESIDENT
CLARK FOR ACHIEVEMENT THAT ACHIEVEMENT.
>> RAYMOND WAS BORN AND RAISED IN BALTIMORE, MARYLAND.
HIS LIFELONG PASSION FOR MOVEMENT AND ATHLETICS LED HIM
TO STUDY SPORTS, MEDICINE AND DANCE AT OR SIGN US
COLLEGE. A SMALL LIBERAL ARTS COLLEGE
IN PENNSYLVANIA. AND RAYMOND'S FIRST BUSINESS
WAS A CONCIERGE CONCIERGE WELLNESS BUSINESS THAT PROVIDED
WELLNESS SERVICES TO HIGH END CONDOS IN PHILADELPHIA.
HE MOVED TO THE BAY AREA IN 2012 INTERESTED IN WORKING
AT THE INTERSECTION OF TECH AND WELLNESS.
>> IN 2020 THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC DEVASTATED BUSINESSES
ACROSS THE CITY INCLUDING RAYMOND'S AND IN HIS SEARCH FOR
A FRESH START HE FOUND HIS WAY TO GLEN PARK A RESILIENT
COMMUNITY THAT WAS ALSO RECOVERING FROM COVID
AND LOOKING TO MOVE FORWARD. AFTER WALKING THROUGH THE
NEIGHBORHOOD AND SPEAKING WITH RESIDENTS AND MERCHANTS,
RAYMOND DECIDED THAT GLEN PARK WAS THE NEIGHBORHOOD FOR HIM
AND HIS BUSINESS. AND FROM DAY ONE HE TOOK
IMMENSE PRIDE IN GLEN PARK AND EMBRACED THE NEIGHBORHOOD,
DEDICATING HIMSELF TO SHAPING IT INTO A PLACE THAT FEELS
WELCOMING TO ALL WHO LIVE, WORK OR VISIT A COMMUNITY SIGN
IN HIS WINDOW LED TO HIS RECRUITMENT TO THE GLEN PARK
MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION BY FELLOW MERCHANTS AND LONGTIME MAYOR OF
GLEN PARK, MARIAN DILLER. HELLO MARIAN.
MADAM MAYOR. AND HE WAS A MEMBER FOR TWO
YEARS BEFORE JOINING THE BOARD IN 2023 AND BEING ELECTED
PRESIDENT IN 2025. >> HE'S EARNED A LEGION OF FANS
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD OTHER MERCHANTS HAVE DESCRIBED HIM AS
THOUGHTFUL AND ATTENTIVE, TAKING THE TIME TO HEAR OUT
EVERY CONCERN, UNDERSTAND ALL THE DETAILS AND MAKE SURE
EVERYONE IS ON THE SAME PAGE WHICH IS PRETTY MUCH IMPOSSIBLE
. BUT THAT IS OUR EXPERIENCE
IN MY OFFICE OF HIM AS WELL. I AND MY TEAM ARE BEYOND
APPRECIATIVE OF THE DEDICATION AND TIME THAT RAYMOND AND THE
REST OF THE GLEN PARK MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION POUR INTO THE
NEIGHBORHOOD WITH IMMENSE GRATITUDE AND APPRECIATION.
WE THANK YOU RAYMOND FOR YOUR SERVICE TO GLEN PARK AND TO THE
CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> AND THE FLOOR IS YOURS. WELL PRESIDENT BANNERMAN, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH. >> AND AS HE MENTIONED, I AM
IN THE HEALTH AND WELLNESS BUSINESS AND ALSO I AM ON THE
BOARD OF SIX. AND TRUTHFULLY I COULD NOT DO
IT WITHOUT THE OTHER MEMBERS OF MY BOARD AND WE ARE CALLED THE
SIX PACK VERY MUCH LIKE CABS BECAUSE EVEN THOUGH POSSIBLY
JUST THE FOUR OF US MAY BE VISIBLE TODAY, ALL SIX OF US
ARE ALWAYS FUNCTIONING AT ALL TIMES.
SO EVEN THOUGH I'M THE ONE ACCEPTING THIS AWARD, IT'S
REALLY ALL OF US TAKING IT ON BECAUSE I COULD NOT DO IT
WITHOUT THEM. >> SO FOR THOSE OF YOU THAT ARE
HERE, PLEASE STAND. >> JANET PAUL MARION BECAUSE
YOU ARE ALL AWESOME ALSO AND SUE AND TERESA WHO COULDN'T
BE HERE TODAY THANK YOU AS WELL AND LET'S GO GLEN PARK.
WE MAY HAVE BEEN THE 35TH BEST NEIGHBORHOOD AND WE ARE
DEFINITELY PUSHING FOR NUMBER ONE.
EVERYONE SAYS IT TAKES A VILLAGE AND WE DEFINITELY HAVE
THE GLEN PARK VILLAGE SO COME CHECK IT OUT WHEN YOU HAVE A
CHANCE. >> THANK YOU SO.
>> ALL RIGHT. MADAM CLERK, LET'S GET BACK TO
ROLL CALL. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR SUBMIT SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU,
MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES, I HAVE TWO ITEMS
TODAY. FIRST, I'M INTRODUCING A
DRAFTING REQUEST TO PROHIBIT THE RETAIL SALE OF NITROUS
OXIDE THE RECREATIONAL USE OF NOT NITROUS OXIDE OFTEN
REFERRED TO AS LAUGHING GAS OR WHIPPETS HAS BEEN EXPLODING
IN POPULARITY IN SAN FRANCISCO AND ACROSS THE US.
THE PRODUCT IS BEING BRAND BRANDED AND COLORFUL CANISTERS
AND MARKETED TO YOUTH UNDER NAMES LIKE GALAXIE GAS MIAMI
MAGIC AND COSMIC GAS. THIS SHOWS A CLEAR PATTERN OF
MANUFACTURERS FOLLOWING THE PLAYBOOK OF BIG TOBACCO
AND VAPE MARKETING DANGEROUS PRODUCTS TO YOUTH
AND VULNERABLE POPULATIONS. >> NITROUS OXIDE ABUSE POSES
REAL HEALTH RISKS. RESEARCH HAS SHOWN THAT
REPEATED USE CAN LEAD TO SERIOUS AND POTENTIALLY LIFE
THREATENING HEALTH COMPLICATIONS INCLUDING NERVE
DAMAGE, PSYCHOSIS AND HEART ATTACK.
>> ONE U.S. STUDY IDENTIFIED DEATHS FROM NITROUS OXIDE
INCREASING 600% BETWEEN 2010 AND 2023.
ANOTHER STUDY SHOWED THAT EMERGENCY ROOM VISITS FROM
NITROUS OXIDE MISUSE HAD SPIKED BY 500% SINCE 2019.
>> SAN DIEGO COUNTY SHERIFF'S CRIME LAB HAS NOTED AN UPTICK
IN CASES OF SUSPECTED DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE OF NITROUS
OXIDE INCLUDING 18 CAR CRASHES IN JUST A ONE YEAR PERIOD.
NITROUS OXIDE CANISTERS CREATE OTHER PROBLEMS TOO.
A SAN FRANCISCO STANDARD ARTICLE LAST YEAR NOTED
WIDESPREAD REPORTS OF CANISTERS BEING FOUND LITTERED ON
STREETS, SIDEWALKS AND PARKS ACROSS THE CITY CAUSING ALARM
FROM DOG OWNERS AND CREATING MORE TRASH.
>> AND THIS IS ONE OF THOSE AREAS WHERE SAN FRANCISCO HAS A
BIT OF CATCHING UP TO DO. DOZENS OF OTHER CITIES ARE
COUNTIES ACROSS OUR STATE HAVE RECENTLY PASSED RETAIL BANS
INCLUDING SAN MATEO, SAN JOSE. SANTA CRUZ, MENDOCINO,
HUMBOLDT, NEWPORT BEACH, ORANGE COUNTY AND ANAHEIM.
WE INTEND TO CRAFT THIS LEGISLATION WITH TARGETED
EXEMPTIONS FOR LEGITIMATE USE IN THE MEDICAL DENTAL, CULINARY
AND AUTOMOTIVE INDUSTRIES. SO I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING
WITH THE CITY ATTORNEY TO CRAFT THIS LEGISLATION WHICH WILL BE
SHAPED BY HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, YOUTH ADVOCATES AND SMALL
BUSINESS INPUT AND AS IT IS FORMED I HOPE IT WILL GAIN YOUR
SUPPORT AS CO-SPONSORS SO THAT WE CAN DO MORE TO KEEP OUR CITY
SAFE AND HEALTHY. AND COLLEAGUES, NEXT I'M
INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION AUTHORIZING THE PORT OF SAN
FRANCISCO TO ENTER INTO A LEASE WITH DYLAN'S TOYS FOR THE
PROPERTY LOCATED AT FOUR NINE JEFFERSON STREET FOR 90.
JEFFERSON IS A COMMERCIAL SPACE AT FISHERMAN'S WHARF THAT HAS
BEEN VACANT FOR MORE THAN 15 YEARS.
THAT SPACE HAD BEEN CHALLENGING BECAUSE OF ITS CONDITION AND A
FUNCTIONALLY OBSOLETE LAYOUT. SO WE'RE GRATEFUL THAT DYLAN'S
TOURS WILL GO INTO THE SPACE. THEY ARE A LOCAL TOUR OPERATOR
AND BIKE RENTAL COMPANY OWNED BY DYLAN DAVID, A SAN FRANCISCO
NATIVE WITH DEEP COMMUNITY ROOTS.
THE BUSINESS IS CURRENTLY LOCATED IN NORTH BEACH BUT IS
SEEKING TO RELOCATE TO FISHERMAN'S WHARF TO HAVE MORE
VISIBILITY AND MORE SPACE. AND THE PARTNERSHIP IS A WIN
FOR FISHERMAN'S WHARF. THEY WILL BREATHE NEW LIFE INTO
THE SPACE, PRODUCE NEW REVENUE FOR A LONG VACANT BUILDING ON
JEFFERSON STREET. IT BUILDS ON THE MOMENTUM WE'RE
SEEING IN FISHERMAN'S WHARF INCLUDING MANY RECENT RETAIL
AND RESTAURANT LEASES AN EXTENSION OF THE SKY STAR
FERRIS WHEEL AND A NEW PLAZA AT THE OLD ALIOTO SPACE CURRENTLY
UNDER CONSTRUCTION. WE'RE ALL VERY EXCITED ABOUT
THIS AND HOPE TO HAVE YOUR SUPPORT AND THE REST OF IT.
>> THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR SAUDER SUPERVISOR
CHERYL COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION
IN SUPPORT OF STATE ASSEMBLY BILL 1974.
ASSEMBLY MEMBER STEPHANIE HAS INTRODUCED A MEASURE TO
AUTHORIZE LAW ENFORCEMENT AGENCIES TO CREATE VOLUNTARY
FIREARM STORAGE PROGRAMS. THIS BUILDS OFF OF THE FIRST
SAFE GUN STORAGE PROGRAM AT POLICE STATIONS IN THE COUNTRY
THAT WE CREATED RIGHT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THANKS TO THE HARD WORK OF LESLIE HEWITT PIERCE'S PLEDGE.
WE ARE BUILDING MOMENTUM. WE'RE SEEING ACTION IN SAN
DIEGO COUNTY. WE'RE SEEING ACTION ACROSS
CALIFORNIA. AND I AM THRILLED THAT ASSEMBLY
MEMBER STEPHANIE IS CONTINUING TO BUILD THIS ACTION NOT ONLY
TO CREATE WAYS TO SAFELY BRING GUNS OUT OF HOMES AT RISK BUT
ALSO TO ENSURE THAT FIREARMS HAVE NOT PREVIOUSLY BEEN
REPORTED AS LOST, STOLEN OR INVOLVED IN A CRIME AND GOING
FURTHER TO CREATE WAYS TO DESTROY FIREARMS THAT ARE NOT
BEING RETRIEVED. THIS IS THOUGHTFUL, THIS IS
EFFECTIVE, THIS IS SAFETY AND I'M VERY EXCITED TO BE IN A
POSITION TO SUPPORT THIS AND I HOPE I CAN HAVE YOUR SUPPORT ON
THIS RESOLUTION. THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR
WALTON THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES TODAY WE HONOR
AND REMEMBER THE LIFE OF CHRIS A WAYNE A SON OF SAN FRANCISCO
RAISED IN BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT WHOSE LIFE REFLECTED A DEEP
COMMITMENT TO FAMILY EDUCATION, MUSIC AND UPLIFTING PEOPLE
AROUND HIM. CHRIS GREW UP AND ATTENDED
SCHOOLS AND AS A FEW AS THE INCLUDING PORTOLA ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, APTOS MIDDLE SCHOOL AND WOODROW WILSON HIGH SCHOOL.
EVEN AS A YOUNG PERSON HE STOOD OUT FOR HIS DETERMINATION
AND TALENT. HE WAS AN AVID BASKETBALL
AND CHESS PLAYER AND IN 1981 HE SERVED AS THE STARTING POINT
GUARD FOR THE WOODROW WILSON SCHOOL VARSITY BASKETBALL
CHAMPIONSHIP TEAM. BUT CHRIS'S IMPACT EXTENDED FAR
BEYOND THE COURT OR THE CLASSROOM AND BEHIND HIS POINT.
HE WAS KNOWN AS A MENTOR AND A GUIDING PRESENCE FOR YOUNG
PEOPLE AND COMMUNITY. HE SHARED HIS TIME AND HIS
GIFTS TEACHING YOUNG PEOPLE HOW TO DANCE.
INTRODUCING HIM TO MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS AND ENCOURAGING
THEM TO STAY IN SCHOOL AND BELIEVE IN THEIR FUTURES.
>> HE UNDERSTOOD THAT SOMETIMES ALL A YOUNG PERSON NEEDS IS
SOMEONE WHO SEES THEIR POTENTIAL AND HELPS TO NURTURE
IT. CHRIS WAS ALSO A GIFTED
MUSICIAN WHO MASTERED BOTH THE DRUMS AND KEYBOARD.
HIS TALENT AND CREATIVITY HELPED HIM SHAPE THE SOUND
AND CULTURE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S HIP HOP AND R&B SCENE.
THROUGH HIS WORK AS A PRODUCER AND LYRICIST HE CONTRIBUTED TO
THE SUCCESS AND LEGACY OF ARTISTS AND GROUPS SUCH AS
CONSCIOUS DAUGHTERS TOO SHORT THE WHISPERS AND THE SHOCKING
EMCEES. ALONG WITH MANY OTHER LOCAL
ARTISTS WHOSE CAREER HE HELPED INSPIRE AND LAUNCH, CHRIS
CARRIED THE SPIRIT AND CREATIVITY OF SAN FRANCISCO
WITH HIM WHEREVER HE WENT. PERFORMING IN MUSICAL SHOWS
AND CONCERTS ACROSS THE U.S. AND YET HE ALWAYS REMAIN DEEPLY
CONNECTED TO THE CITY THAT RAISED HIM.
CHRIS WILL BE REMEMBERED AS A PIONEER OF SAN FRANCISCO MUSIC
AND A BELOVED MEMBER OF HIS COMMUNITY.
A LOVING, CARING AND CHARISMATIC SOUL WHO
BELIEVED IN PEOPLE AND INVESTED IN THE NEXT GENERATION.
>> HIS LEGACY LIVES ON THROUGH HIS DAUGHTER THE MUSIC HE
CREATED, THE ARTISTS HE UPLIFTED AND THE COUNTLESS
YOUNG PEOPLE WHOSE LIVES HE TOUCHED.
MAY HIS MEMORY CONTINUE TO INSPIRE OUR CITY FOR
GENERATIONS TO COME. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> SUPERVISOR WONG. THANK YOU, COLLEAGUES.
TODAY I'M INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING FEBRUARY
AS CHILDREN'S DENTAL HEALTH MONTH IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF
SAN FRANCISCO. TOOTH DECAY IS 100%
PREVENTABLE. YET IT REMAINS ONE THE MOST
COMMON CHRONIC DISEASE IN CHILDREN.
AND DENTAL HYGIENE IS OFTEN DISMISSED AS COSMETIC WHEN IT'S
ACTUALLY FUNDAMENTAL TO PHYSICAL HEALTH.
WHEN DECAY GOES UNTREATED IT CAN LEAD TO NOT ONLY PAIN BUT
ALSO SERIOUS INFECTIONS AND IT CAN UNDERMINE A CHILD'S ABILITY
TO SLEEP, EAT AND FOCUS AT SCHOOL.
>> IN SFO CITY DURING THE 2024 TO 2025 SCHOOL YEAR 26.6% OF
KINDERGARTNERS HAD EXPERIENCED CAVITIES.
AND THE DISPARITIES ARE STARK. THE RATE OF UNTREATED TOOTH
DECAY AMONG BLACK OR AFRICAN-AMERICAN CHILDREN IS
27.2% MORE THAN 3.5 TIMES THE RATE AMONG WHITE CHILDREN AT
7.1%. SOME NEIGHBORHOODS INCLUDING
CHINATOWN, THE MISSION BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT CONTINUE TO BEAR
A PARTICULARLY HIGH BURDEN. THIS RESOLUTION ALSO RECOGNIZES
THE WORK ALREADY HAPPENING THROUGH S.F. COMMUNITY BASED
DENTAL SERVICES AND PARTNERS LIKE CAVITY FREE S.F. INCLUDING
COMMUNITY ACTION ALLIANCES THAT ENGAGE PARENTS AND LOCAL
PARTNERS TO PROMOTE PREVENTION AND ACCESS IN WAYS THAT FIT
EACH COMMUNITY. RECOGNIZING CHILDREN'S DENTAL
HEALTH MONTH IS A SIMPLE STEP BUT IT SENDS A CLEAR MESSAGE WE
SUPPORT PREVENTION. WE SUPPORT EQUITY AND WE WANT
EVERY CHILD IN SAN FRANCISCO TO BE HEALTHY, PAIN FREE AND READY
TO LEARN. I'M ALSO INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION IN SUPPORT OF ASSEMBLY BILLS AB 18 AND AB
1831 AUTHORED BY ASSEMBLY MEMBERS LIZ ORTEGA AND PATRICK
AARONS TO ADVANCE FAIRNESS AND ACCOUNTABILITY AT THE
CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY SYSTEM.
SAN FRANCISCO HAS A DIRECT STAKE IN THIS.
WE'RE HOME TO SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY AND OUR
STUDENTS, FACULTY AND STAFF DEPEND ON A STRONG, STABLE
AND AFFORDABLE PUBLIC UNIVERSITY.
AND AS A CITY WE HAVE A LONG STANDING COMMITMENT TO THE
RIGHTS OF WORKERS TO ORGANIZE, BARGAIN IN GOOD FAITH AND HAVE
AGREEMENTS HONORED. I RECENTLY SPOKE AT A RALLY AT
SAN FRANCISCO STATE. STANDING SHOULDER TO SHOULDER
OF LABOR ON BEHALF OF CSU WORKERS THE PEOPLE WHO KEEP THE
CAMPUS RUNNING EVERY DAY WHO DESERVE RESPECT, STABILITY
AND FAIRNESS. AB 1818 ADDRESSES A FUNDAMENTAL
PRINCIPLE WHEN A CONTRACT IS INCORPORATED AND APPROVED IT
SHOULD BE HONORED. CSU WORKERS HAVE RAISED
CONCERNS THAT THE ADMINISTRATION HAS RELIED ON A
LOOPHOLE TIED TO DELAY, WITHHOLD OR EVEN RESCIND IT
PROMISED STEP INCREASES AND RAISES AFTER AGREEMENTS
WERE REACHED. AB 1818 IS INTENDED TO CLOSE
THAT LOOPHOLE BY PREVENTING POST HOC FUNDING RELATED
TECHNICALITIES FROM BEING USED TO REOPEN OR NULLIFY WAGE TERMS
AFTER BARGAINING IS DONE SO WORKERS CAN RELY ON COMMITMENTS
THEY EARNED. AB 1831 IS ABOUT KEEPING
EXECUTIVE PAY IN CHECK. CSU IS SETS A CLEAR CAP ON WHAT
CSU CAN PAY CERTAIN TOP ADMINISTRATORS AND MANAGERS
TIED TO A BENCHMARK BASED ON THE GOVERNOR'S PAY.
IT ALSO SAYS CSU CAN'T GIVE THOSE EXECUTIVES A RAISE.
IN ANY YEAR WHEN CSU RAISES TUITION ON STUDENTS AND IT
REQUIRES CSU TO UNDO A 2025 DECISION THAT INCREASE
EXECUTIVE COMPENSATION IN PLAIN TERMS IT IS IF STUDENTS ARE
ASKED TO PAY MORE. CSU LEADERSHIP SHOULDN'T BE
PAYING ITSELF MORE AT THE SAME TIME AND THERE SHOULD BE CLEAR
LIMITS TO ON TOP PAY. TAKEN TOGETHER THESE BILLS
PROMOTE A SIMPLE CONSISTENT THEME.
HONOR COMMITMENTS TO WORKERS AND ENSURE EXECUTIVE PAY
PRACTICES ARE ACCOUNTABLE ESPECIALLY WHEN STUDENTS ARE
ASKED TO PAY MORE. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WONG SUPERVISOR
FIELDER UC TO BE RE REFERRED. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK.
>> COLLEAGUES TODAY HAVE AN IN MEMORIAM FOR A BELOVED
DISTRICT NINE RESIDENT AND RENOWNED ARTIST
AND COMMUNITY BUILDER ARTHUR ART KOCH WHO SPENT HIS LIFE
ENRICHING THE ENVIRONMENT AROUND HIM WITH COLOR
CREATIVITY AND LOVE FOR HIS COMMUNITY.
ART MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO IN 1984 AND AFTER GETTING
MARRIED AND HAVING A CHILD HIS BELOVED SON VLADIMIR HE BOUGHT
A HOUSE IN THE PORTOLA IN 1994. >> FOR OVER 40 YEARS ART
CONTRIBUTED SO MUCH TO SAN FRANCISCO AS AN ACTIVE AND AVID
COMMUNITY ORGANIZER. >> BUT HE WILL BE REMEMBERED
CHIEFLY FOR HIS ARTISTIC PURSUITS WHICH REFLECTED HIS
DEEP LOVE FOR THE MISSION. >> BERNAL AND THE PORTOLA BY
DOCUMENTING STREET FAIRS DEMONSTRATE TIONS AND COMMUNITY
LIFE IN HIS PHOTOGRAPHY PAINTINGS, MURALS AND VIDEO
PRODUCTIONS. ART MET HIS BEAUTIFUL
AND AMAZING SECOND WIFE LISA WHILE STUDYING ART AT COLUMBIA
COLLEGE IN THE 80S. THEY RECONNECTED 30 YEARS LATER
AND WERE MARRIED HERE AT CITY HALL OFFICIATED BY MY
PREDECESSOR FORMER SUPERVISOR RONEN.
TOGETHER ART AND LISA SERVED ON THE ARTS AND BEAUTIFICATION
COMMITTEE AT THE PORTLAND NEIGHBORHOOD ASSOCIATION
AND FOR SEVERAL YEARS RAN AN ART AND PHOTOGRAPHY STUDIO
IN THE PORTOLA. ART CONSISTENTLY EXPRESSED A
DEEP APPRECIATION FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD HE LIVED
AND WORKED IN THROUGH HIS PIECES PAINTING BEAUTIFUL
AND LARGE SCALE MURALS TO REFLECT THE PORTLAND DIVERSITY
AND CULTURAL SIGNIFICANCE INCLUDING A PIECE COMMISSIONED
DURING THE PANDEMIC THAT UPLIFTED PEOPLE'S SPIRITS
AND GAVE THE NEIGHBORHOOD A SENSE OF HOPE.
>> IN 2018 ART WAS COMMISSIONED BY SAN FRANCISCO BEAUTIFUL TO
PAINT EIGHT CITYSCAPES OF DIFFERENT NEIGHBORHOODS IN SAN
FRANCISCO MATCHED WITH POETRY AND DISPLAYED ON THE INSIDE OF
MUNI BUSSES WITH THE THEME CONNECTED COMMUNITIES.
>> THE DISTRICT NINE OFFICE HAS HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF DISPLAYING
A GALLERY OF HIS ARTWORK FOR THE LAST FOUR YEARS AND EVERY
PERSON WHO HAS STEPPED THROUGH OUR DOOR HAS MARVELED AT THE
BREADTH AND BEAUTY OF HIS REPRESENTS PORTIONS OF
NEIGHBORHOOD SCENES AND CELEBRATIONS.
>> IN RESPONSE TO ACCOMMODATION HE RECEIVED HERE AT THIS BOARD
IN 2023 HE SHARED QUOTE WHAT IS CITIZENSHIP BY WORKING
RESPECTFULLY AND RESPONSIBLY WITH OTHERS AND FOR YOUR
COMMUNITY? >> PEOPLE WHO DISPLAY
CITIZENSHIP TAKE CARE OF THEMSELVES AND THEIR
COMMUNITIES. >> CITIZENSHIP REQUIRES SOCIAL
AWARENESS, RELATIONSHIPS, SKILLS AND RESPONSIBLE DECISION
MAKING. ONE OF ART'S DREAMS WAS TO
CREATE AN ART NIGHT AT CITY HALL TO CELEBRATE THE CITY'S
MANY CREATIVES AND TO UPLIFT THE IMPORTANCE OF ARTS
AND CULTURE TO OUR DIVERSE NEIGHBORHOODS.
GIVEN THE THREATS TO ARTS AND CULTURE IN SAN FRANCISCO
TODAY, I'M HOPEFUL THAT TOGETHER WE CAN MAKE HIS VISION
A REALITY AND COMMIT TO SUPPORTING THESE IMPORTANT
COMMUNITY ASSETS AND PERHAPS INDEED HAVE AN ART NIGHT AT
CITY HALL IN THE NEAR FUTURE. >> ART ALWAYS TOOK CARE OF HIS
COMMUNITY AND CELEBRATED THE VIBRANCY AND BEAUTY OF LIFE
IN THE PORTOLA BERNAL AND MISSION THROUGHOUT HIS
LIFE'S WORK. I OFFER MY DIVAS CONDOLENCES TO
VLADIMIR, HIS SON AND HIS WIFE AND PARTNER IN ART
AND COMMUNITY. LISA AND HER KIDS WHO ARE HERE
TODAY TO WITNESS THIS TRIBUTE. HIS LEGACY LIVES ON IN PUBLIC
MURALS HE PAINTED AND THE GALLERY OF HIS WORK THAT HIS
SON HOPES TO CREATE IN THEIR HOME IN THE PORTOLA.
REST IN POWER ART COACH WE WILL DEARLY MISS YOU.
>> COLLEAGUES OUTSIDE. >> TWO ITEMS INTRODUCED TODAY
THAT BOTH SERVE TO PRESERVE AND HONOR THE LEGACY OF LATIN
ROCK MUSIC IN THE MISSION DISTRICT INCLUDING SAN
FRANCISCO'S OWN CARLOS SANTANA. >> THE FIRST IS A RESOLUTION
INITIATING THE DESIGNATION OF THE LATIN ROCK HOUSE LOCATED AT
2880 25TH STREET AS A HISTORICAL LANDMARK OWNED BY
LOCAL MUSICIAN RICHARD SEGOVIA. THE LATIN ROCK HOUSE IS
RECOGNIZED FOR ITS CULTURAL SIGNIFICANCE AND MURAL
DEPICTING OVER 87 LOCAL LATIN ROCK AND LATINO MUSICIANS.
THE SECOND IS A RESOLUTION SUPPORTING A COMMEMORATIVE
PLAQUE TO BE INSTALLED IN FRONT OF 405 MULLEN AVENUE, THE SITE
WHERE SANTANA LIVES IN BERNAL HEIGHTS DURING WHICH HE AND HIS
BAND MATES PRODUCED HIS BREAKTHROUGH ALBUM THAT
CEMENTED HIS LEGACY AS A LATIN ROCK LEGEND.
THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR
FIELDER. MR. PRESIDENT, SEEING NO NAMES
ON THE ROSTER, THAT CONCLUDES THE INTRODUCTION OF NEW
BUSINESS AND LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT AT THIS TIME THE BOARD
WELCOMES TO HEAR YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO
SPEAK PLEASE LINE UP ON THE RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
WE ARE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
I HATE TO INTERRUPT YOU BUT WE WANT TO HEAR FROM EVERYONE.
YOU ARE ABLE TO SPEAK TO THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED ITEMS 34
THROUGH 40 ON THE ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE OR
OTHER GENERAL MATTERS THAT ARE NOT ON THE PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT
MUST BE WITHIN THE BOARD'S SUBJECT MATTER JURISDICTION.
>> ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT HAS BEEN REPORTED OUT TO THE BOARD
BY AN APPROPRIATE COMMITTEE WHERE THE PUBLIC COMMENT
REQUIREMENT OCCURRED. >> ALL RIGHT, LET'S HEAR FROM
OUR FIRST SPEAKER. WELCOME.
>> NOW FOLKS DETERMINE THEY DON'T LIVE IN A LONG SITTING
EXPERIMENT THIS YOU WANT TO SEE THE CITY OF WEST 32 SYMBOLS
GOOD HUMAN MESSAGE LOOKS AT CITY FEEL AND ACHIEVABLE
CAPACITY LIMITS SUCH AS SWIFTLY THIS MAN PROBABLY MORE THAN
MEETS SHE ALSO FANCIES COULD NOT UTILIZE A TELEVISION LOCALE
THE SAN FRANCISCO HERE SO IF IT WASN'T YOU SAY THE THIS PTA
SEASON IS ALL ABOUT UNIQUE MOM THE PROBLEM HERE ALL SO THAT
YOU ARE JUSTIFIED TOURISM THAT'S WHERE I SEE CONSUMER ALL
NEOPETS COULD THEY DO ALL MR. MUST BAR COMPLAINT ON YOUR T C
SAY THAT THEY DON'T DON'T IT DOUBLE IT UP ON CONSTITUTION IS
JUNIOR LAS PALMAS SO SUE LEE A BIT OF A FEEL OF A NEW SYSTEM
NON-COMPETE ONLY COME SAY IF YOU DON'T HAVE A CLEAR FEAR THE
DOSSIER IT FILES ITS DOSSIER MOBILE PHONE NOT NO DOSSIER
DON'T ALL SAY NO BUT ALBA HD NO ALBA ALLEGED STEINER OKAY SO
OTHERWISE YOUR STORIES ON THE FEATURES OF COURSE DO POLICY
YOU DON'T GLOW DON'T BESMIRCH YOU SEE BUT BECAUSE THAT'S A DE
FORMA TO THE YOURSELF BECAUSE SHE ACTUALLY WOULD HAVE NEEDED
YOUR OPINION THOSE ISSUES CONTROL I GET MOVE ABOUT THIS
ALONE AS RESOURCES MACHINERY CLIMATIQUES DON'T LOVE CALLED
COMPANY ETAPA IT'S UP THAT PASSION FOR BANJO MERCY LET'S
HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE AND IF THERE ARE ANY
OTHER MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE
BOARD, PLEASE STEP OVER IN LINE OTHERWISE THIS MAY BE OUR LAST
SPEAKER WELCOME BOARD OF SUPERVISOR AND MAYOR OFFICE OF
SOUTH CISCO THE TITLE OF THE SPEECHES SPEAK TYPISTS.
WHEN I WAS A KID AROUND EIGHT YEARS OLD I TOOK A TYPING CLASS
IN ROOSEVELT MOTOR SCHOOL AND THE RICHMOND DISTRICT OF
SAN FRANCISCO. I FELL IN LOVE WITH THE TASK I
SPENT HOURS WRITING A BUST OF TO HAVE TEACHER IN MY LAB TO
MEMORIZE THE MONARCHY PAPER TO VISUALIZE HOW TWO FINGERS PRESS
THE KEYS ON A TYPEWRITER. I WANTED TO BE THE WORLD'S
FASTEST TYPIST. I SPENT OBSESSIONS ALL THE WAY
TO MY ADULTHOOD. SOMETHING HAPPENED THE FIRST
YEAR IN CITY COLLEGE OF SAN CISCO.
I SPENT TWO YEARS IN HIGH SCHOOL WORKING IN FOOT LOCKER,
SAW SOME BUNNIES I HAD SOME MACS AND A PC.
MY FRIEND CAME OVER AND STOLE O'S TO WALK.
I WAS BLOWN AWAY. EVERYTHING IS POSSIBLE AS LONG
AS I HAVE IMAGINATION TO PURSUE.
I NEVER MADE IT TO LAW HIGH SCHOOL SO I SETTLE FOR GEORGE
WASHINGTON HIGH SCHOOL AFTER SPENDING THREE YEARS I TRANSFER
UC BERKELEY WITH UNDECLARED MAJOR.
I WON A COMPUTER SCIENCE MAJOR THAT WAS MY PASSION.
I'M A BERKELEY DROPOUT. EVENTUALLY I GRADUATE AT UC
DAVIS OF A COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING DEGREE WHILE INDOOR
IN BERKELEY I SHARED TOO MUCH TO FRIENDS SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL. MY FRIEND CLARK HIMSELF TYPING
95 WORDS PER MINUTE. I WAS DISAPPOINTED I COULD ONLY
TYPE 90 WORDS PER MINUTE SO I DROPPED MY PASSION TO PURSUE
INSTEAD COMPUTER SCIENCE I LOVE ALL ASPECTS OF COMPUTING.
AFTERWARDS I WORKED IN SYMANTEC, NETSCAPE BAY
NETWORKS, NORTEL CASH FLOW AND STARTUP CORNER WHERE
IN 2002 I MET UP WITH MARTIN GREENBERG, THE ARCHITECT OF
NETSCAPE. HE'S A FOUNDER AND CHIEF
TECHNOLOGY OFFICER OF CORNINGWARE WHERE I WORKED FOR
SIX YEARS FROM 2000 TO 2008. THE REASON WHY I STAND HERE IS
BECAUSE I PRONOUNCED MYSELF CHIEF SOFTWARE ARCHITECT OF X A
I MY PRIOR TO PRINCIPAL BOW DISPLAYING TRAFFIC LIGHTS PULL
. I'M EXHILARATED TO HAVE MY
VISION EXPOSED TO WHERE AIR BROWSING A RANCH FOR FLYING
CARS THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> ALL RIGHT MR. PRESIDENT PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSE.
>> MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR FOUR ADOPTION OF THAT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 34 THROUGH 40 ITEMS 34 THROUGH 40
WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION BUT WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE
A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON
FIRST READING TODAY ANY MEMBER MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON
FIRST READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR WANG.
>> TWO THINGS I'D LIKE TO ADD MY NAME TO ITEM 34 SUPPORTING A
STRONG INDEPENDENT DEPARTMENT OF VETERAN AFFAIRS AND SECONDLY
,I WOULD LIKE TO MAKE A MOTION TO CONTINUE HOLD HOLD ON THAT.
>> BUT MAYBE LET'S COVER ITEM 37.
YES, WE'LL TAKE THAT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WONG SUPERVISOR MELGAR, I WANT TO BE ADDED AS A
CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 38 PLEASE NOTED.
>> ALL RIGHT. SO MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE HAVE
SEVERED 37 AND ON THE REMAINING BALANCE OF THE ITEMS CAN YOU
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 34 THROUGH 36 AND 38 THROUGH 40
SUPERVISE SIR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MARK WOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER
SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I THERE ARE 11 EYES THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED AND MOTION IS APPROVED
AND MADAM CLERK COULD YOU PLEASE CALL ITEM 37 ITEM 37
RESOLUTION TO URGE THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT AND DEPARTMENT OF TECHNOLOGY TO PRIORITIZE THE
RESTORATION OF SAN FRANCISCO'S OUTDOOR PUBLIC WARNING SYSTEM
IN TSUNAMI EVACUATIONS ZONES AND COASTAL AREAS AND TO
ALLOCATE FUNDING FOR THIS CRITICAL PUBLIC SAFETY
INFRASTRUCTURE SUPERVISOR WONG THANK YOU PRESIDENT MAINLAND
FOR BEING AHEAD OF BEING A LITTLE BIT COLLEAGUES I LIKE TO
MAKE A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS ITEM TO THE CALL.
>> THE CHAIR I THINK YOU WANT TO CONTINUE IT FOR ONE WEEK.
>> I'LL TAKE THAT AND I WOULD LIKE TO SECOND THAT AND I THINK
WE CAN TAKE THAT EMOTION. >> MR. PRESIDENT, CAN WE JUST
PUT THE DATE ON THE CALENDAR? OH, SURE WOULD BE WHEN?
WEEK IS FEBRUARY. MARCH THIRD.
YES. OKAY.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT MOTION WITHOUT OBJECTION
AND WITHOUT OBJECTION. THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK, DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA
ITEMS? >> I HAVE NONE TO REPORT.
>> MR. PRESIDENT, COULD YOU PLEASE READ THE IN MEMORIAM?
YES. TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS
OR ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR FIELDER FOR THE LATE MR. ARTHUR
KOTCH ON BEHALF OF PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR THE LATE MR.
WAYNE JUSTEMENT ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR THE LATE
MS. AND DUFFY MR. EDWARD JOSEPH REEDY, MR. JOHN BARRY AND MR.
BRYAN SPEARS AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR THE LATE
MR. CHRISTOPHER A WAYNE AND I BELIEVE THAT BRINGS US TO THE
END OF OUR AGENDA MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS
BEFORE US TODAY? >> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS
FOR TODAY THAN WE ARE ADJOURNED